華 納 兄 弟 影 業     出 品
艾 文 · 溫 克 勒     制 片 作 品
馬 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯     電 影 作 品
領 銜 主 演:  羅 伯 特 · 德 尼 羅
領 銜 主 演:  雷 · 利 奧 塔
領 銜 主 演:  喬 · 佩 西
領 銜 主 演:  洛 蘭 · 布 蕾 科
領 銜 主 演:  保 羅 · 索 維 諾
本 片 改 編 自 真 實 故 事
紐約  1970年
什麼聲音
What the fuck is that?
吉米
Jimmy?
- 什麼事  - 我是不是撞到什麼了
- What's up? - Did I hit something?
到底是什麼
What the fuck is that?
是不是爆胎啦
Maybe you got a flat?
不是啦
No.
他媽的  最好停下來看看
What the fuck? You better pull over and see.
他還活著  你他媽的真是人渣
He's still alive. You fucking piece of shit!
去死吧  婊子養的  看著我
Die, you motherfucker! Look at me!
從我有記憶開始  我就想成為黑幫分子
As far back as I can remember, I always wanted to be a gangster.
片 名:  好 家 伙
又 譯:  盜 亦 有 道 / 四 海 好 家 伙
監 制:  芭 芭 拉 · 德 菲 納
本 片 改 編 自 尼 古 拉 斯 · 派 勒 吉 所 著 『黑 幫 兄 弟』 一 書
編 劇
尼 古 拉 斯 · 派 勒 吉 & 馬 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯
制 片:  艾 文 · 溫 克 勒
導 演:  馬 丁 · 斯 科 塞 斯
對我來說
To me,
成為黑幫分子比當選美國總統還好
being a gangster was better than being president of the United States.
紐約東區  布魯克林  1955年
在我去計程車站找零工之前
Even before I first wandered into the cabstand for an after-school job...
我就知道我要成為他們的一份子
I knew I wanted to be a part of them.
我有種歸屬感
It was there that I knew I belonged.
對我來說是一種成就感  在一個充滿了無名小卒的環境中
To me, it meant being somebody in a neighborhood full of nobodies.
他們不像別人  他們能隨心所欲
They weren't like anybody else. They did whatever they wanted.
他們在消防栓前面停車而從來也不會被開罰單
They double-parked in front of a hydrant, nobody ever gave them a ticket.
夏天通宵賭撲克
In the summer, when they played cards all night...
也沒人敢叫警察
nobody ever called the cops.
東尼·史達斯  你好嗎
Tony Stacks. How are you?
杜迪·西席羅
Tuddy Cicero.
這就是加拿希小子嗎
Could this be the Canarsie Kid?
- 你好嗎  - 蠻好的
- How are you? - Good.
杜迪
Tuddy.
杜迪的大哥保利是整個社區的大老闆
Tuddy ran the cabstand and the Bella Vista Pizzeria...
他替他打理計程車站和貝拉維斯塔披薩屋等地點
and other places for his brother, Paul, who was the boss of the neighborhood.
保利看起來動作很慢
Paulie might have moved slow...
那是因為保利不需要為任何人做事
but it was only because Paulie didn't have to move for anybody.
- 都是你不好  - 是你先開始的
- It's your fault. - You started it.
我先開始的  是你不好
I started it? It's your fault.
起先我父母都很高興我在對街找到一份工作
At first my parents loved that I found a job across the street from the house.
我父親是愛爾蘭人  他十一歲就被送去工作了
My father, who was Irish, was sent to work at the age of 11.
他很高興我找到工作
He liked that I got myself a job.
他常說美國孩子都被慣壞了
He always used to say that American kids were spoiled lazy.
- 爸  再見  - 再見
- Bye, Dad. - Bye.
再見  米奇
See you, Mikey.
再見  亨利
Bye, Henry.
亨利  過馬路要小心呀
Henry! Watch how you cross!
記得帶牛奶回來
Bring back milk!
我媽媽也高興呀  當她知道西席羅家
My mother was happy after she found out that the Ciceros...
和她是從西西里同一個地區出來的  對我媽媽而言
came from the same part of Sicily as she did. To my mother...
就像她的禱告都應驗了
that was the answer to all her prayers.
我是世上最幸運的小孩
I was the luckiest kid in the world.
我可以到任何地方  做任何事
I could go anywhere, I could do anything.
我認識每一個人  大家也都認識我
I knew everybody, and everybody knew me.
兄弟們開車來  杜迪就讓我
Wiseguys would pull up and Tuddy would toss me their keys...
幫他們停凱迪拉克車
and let me park their Cadillacs.
那時候我還是個小鬼
Here I am, this little kid,
坐在方向盤後面  連路都看不見
I can't even see over the steering wheel...
就能停凱迪拉克了
and I'm parking Cadillacs.
可是  沒多久
But it wasn't too long...
我父母就反對我在計程車站的工作了
before my parents changed their minds about my job at the cabstand.
給你媽媽跟妹妹
For your mother and sister.
對他們來說  計程站的工作只是零工  對我
For them, the cabstand was supposed to be a part-time job. But for me...
卻是全天候
it was definitely full-time.
我唯一想做的事
That's all I wanted to do.
像我爸爸這種人永遠也不會瞭解  我是其中的一份子
People like my father could never understand, but I was a part of something.
我有所屬  他們以成人待我
I belonged. I was treated like a grown-up.
告訴他519
Tell him 519.
每天我都在學些有用的技巧
Every day I was learning to score.
這裏一塊錢  那裏一塊錢
A dollar here, a dollar there.
我好像活在夢幻裏
I was living in a fantasy.
今天在學校還順利嗎
Did you have a good day at school?
父親總是非常生氣
My father was always pissed off.
他氣自己賺錢太少
Pissed that he made such lousy money...
他氣弟弟米奇活在輪椅上
pissed that my kid brother Michael was in a wheelchair.
他氣我們一家七口擠在一間小房子裏
He was pissed that there were seven of us living in such a tiny house.
你跟我說說這個
Tell me about this.
是學校來的信
It's a letter from school.
信上說你已經幾個月沒上學了
It says you haven't been there in months.
幾個月了
In months!
你是個沒用的混球
You're a bum!
你長大想做個流浪漢嗎
Want to grow up to be a bum?
過了一陣子之後  他氣我整天泡在計程車站
After a while, he was mostly pissed because I hung around the cabstand.
他知道站裏有些什麼勾當
He knew what went on at that cabstand.
我經常挨揍  可是我已經不在乎了
Every once in a while, I'd have to take a beating. But by then, I didn't care.
就我看來
The way I saw it...
每個人都有挨揍的時候
everybody takes a beating sometime.
- 我不能再送貨了  - 什麼  你這樣會把所有事都搞砸
- I can't make any more deliveries. - What? You'll fuck everything up.
我老爸說他會殺了我  你看
My dad says he'll kill me. Look.
跟我來
Come on with me.
- 那是送信到你家的郵差嗎  - 不是
- Is that him, kid? - No.
- 那一個呢  - 也不是
- How about him? - No.
- 那個就是  - 去找他
- That's the guy. - Get him.
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 人渣  - 你這塊狗屎  給我過來
- Scumbag. - Come here, you piece of shit.
- 認識這個小鬼嗎  - 認得呀
- Know this kid? - Yeah.
- 你知道他住哪裏嗎  - 知道
- Know where he lives? - Yeah.
- 這家的信是由你送的嗎  - 是的
- You deliver mail to his house? - Yeah.
從現在起  任何從學校寄給他家的信都給我
From now on, any letter from that school to his house comes directly here.
- 你懂嗎  - 懂
- Understand? - Yeah.
假如再有一封學校的信送進那小鬼家裏的話
Another letter from that school goes to that kid's house...
你會被塞進烤披薩的爐子裏
in the fucking oven you'll go, head first.
就這樣  再也沒有缺課的來信  再也沒有學校的來信
That was it. No more letters from truant officers. No letters from school.
其實  任何信件都沒有了
In fact, no more letters from anybody.
最後  經過幾星期  我媽媽去郵局抱怨了
Finally after a few weeks, my mother went to the post office to complain.
從那以後  我怎麼能回到學校去發誓效忠國旗
How could I go to school after that...
我又怎能坐在那裏聽政府如何好的屁話呢
and pledge allegiance to the flag and sit through good government bullshit?
保利最恨電話了  他不肯在家裏裝電話
Paulie hated phones. He wouldn't have one in his house.
米奇打來了  要不要我回他電話
Mickey called. Want me to call him back?
好吧  打過去
All right, make the call.
他的電話都是由別人傳達給他
He got all his calls second hand. Then you'd have to call the people back...
然後手下再從公用電話回電
from an outside phone.
你有沒有五分錢  幫我打個電話給他
Got a nickel? Get him on the phone.
有幾個混混整天就是忙著幫保利接電話
There were guys, that's all they did all day, was take care of Paulie's calls.
對一個整天忙碌不停的人來說  他很少跟人說話
For a guy who moved all day long, Paulie didn't talk to six people.
假如工會有了問題或彩票上有爭議
If there was a union problem or, say, a beef in the numbers...
只有高級幹部可以跟保利商議
only the top guys could meet with Paulie to discuss the problem.
保利討厭開會  凡事都是一對一解決
Everything was one-on-one. Paulie hated conferences.
他不要別人聽到他說的話
He didn't want anybody hearing what he said...
或聽到別人說給他聽的話
and he didn't want anybody listening to what he was being told.
好幾百人以保利當靠山  他們所賺的都給保利一份
Hundreds of guys depended on Paulie, he got a piece of everything they made.
那就是保護費  就像在西西里  只不過這是美國
It was a tribute, like in the old country, except they were doing it in America.
保利也只不過保護他們不被別人欺侮詐騙
All they got from Paulie was protection from other guys looking to rip them off.
就是這樣  FBI始終搞不懂這一點
That's what it's all about. That's what the FBI could never understand.
保利所做的
What Paulie and the Organization does...
就是保護那些無法受警察保護的人
is offer protection for people who can't go to the cops. That's it.
保利就像是兄弟們的警察局長
That's all it is. They're like the police department for wiseguys.
別人看我的眼光都不一樣  因為我和大人物在一起
People looked at me differently, and they knew I was with somebody.
我連禮拜天買新鮮麵包都用不著排隊了
I didn't have to wait in line at the bakery on Sunday mornings for fresh bread.
老闆知道我跟誰在一起
The owner knew who I was with...
他會從櫃檯後面走出來  不管有多少人在等
and he'd come from around the counter. No matter how many were waiting...
他都會先招呼我
I was taken care of first.
鄰居再也不將車停在我們車道上了
Our neighbors didn't park in our driveway anymore...
雖然我們沒有車  我十三歲的時候
even though we didn't have a car. At 13...
我賺的錢已經比附近的大人還多
I was making more money than most of the grown-ups around.
我的錢多得花不完  要什麼有什麼
I had more money than I could spend. I had it all.
有一天  附近幾個孩子們還幫我媽把菜拎回家
One day, some neighborhood kids carried my mother's groceries all the way home.
知道為什麼嗎
You know why?
因為他們尊敬我
It was out of respect.
媽媽  你認為如何
Hi, Mom, what do you think?
- 你看我的鞋  很棒吧  - 老天呀
- Look at my shoes, aren't they great? - My God.
你看上去像個黑幫分子
You look like a gangster.
他們射中我了  救命
They shot me. Help!
亨利  把門關上
Henry, shut the door.
那是我第一次看到槍擊
That was the first time I had ever seen anyone shot.
別在店裏搞這些  天吶
Can't have that in here. Jesus Christ!
我不准在這裏弄這種事
I can't have that in this joint.
我記得我為那個人感到難過
I remember feeling bad about the guy...
我也記得或許杜迪是對的
but I also remember feeling that maybe Tuddy was right.
我知道保利不要有任何人死在屋裏
I knew Paulie didn't want anybody dying in the building.
你真是個大白癡  你糟蹋了八條圍裙
You're a real jerk. You wasted eight fucking aprons on this guy.
你他媽的到底怎麼了  我要讓這個小鬼長進一點
What the hell's wrong with you? I got to toughen this kid up.
那真是一段光彩的日子
It was a glorious time.
到處都是兄弟們
And wiseguys were all over the place.
那是在阿帕拉欽事件之前
It was before Apalachin and before Crazy Joe...
在瘋子周和老大開戰前
decided to take on a boss and start a war.
我就是那時候認清世界
It was when I met the world.
並認識吉米·康威
And it was when I first met Jimmy Conway.
他頂多不過二十八九歲
He couldn't have been more than 28 or 29 at the time...
但已經是個傳奇人物了
but he was already a legend.
他只要一走進來  廳裏所有的人就像發瘋一樣
He'd walk in the door and everybody who worked the room just went wild.
幫他開門  就給一百塊小費
He'd give the doorman $100 just for opening the door.
他常塞百元大鈔給那些發牌跟主持賭局的人
He'd give hundreds to the dealers and the guys who ran the games.
連酒保也有百元小費  只要冰塊夠冰的話
The bartender got $100 just for keeping the ice cubes cold.
讓愛爾蘭人來贏你們這些意大利人的錢了
The Irishman is here to take all you guineas' money.
- 你要不要喝一杯  - 給我一杯七喜加海馬七威士忌
- Want a drink? - Give me a 7 and 7.
- 來見見這個小子亨利  - 很高興認識你
- I'd like you to meet the kid Henry. - How you doing?
- 謝謝你  - 繼續上酒
- Thank you. - Keep them coming.
吉米是全城當時最令人敬畏的人之一
Jimmy was one of the most feared guys in the city.
他第一次被關起來時才十一歲
He was first locked up at 11...
十六歲就替他老闆殺人了
and he was doing hits for mob bosses when he was 16.
吉米一點也不在乎殺人  那是他的職業
See, hits never bothered Jimmy. It was business.
但是吉米真正的愛好
But what Jimmy really loved to do...
是偷東西
what he really loved to do was steal.
那對他來說是一種享受
He actually enjoyed it.
吉米就是那種支持電影裏的壞蛋的那種人
Jimmy was the kind of guy who rooted for the bad guys in the movies.
把你的錢包給我
Give me your wallet.
你也許知道我們是誰  我們可清楚的知道你的底細  懂嗎
You might know who we are, but we know who you are. Understand?
他是當時城裏最大的劫車犯之一
He was one of the city's biggest hijackers...
劫運酒車  運煙車  運蝦  刮鬍刀  龍蝦等等
of booze, cigarettes, razor blades, shrimp and lobsters.
蝦跟龍蝦是最好的貨  很快就銷出去了
Shrimp and lobsters were best. They went really fast.
幾乎所有的劫案都是不用暴力的
Almost all of them were gimmies. They just gave it up, no problem.
他們甚至稱他為紳士吉米
They called him Jimmy the Gent.
幫幫小姐
Help the lady.
開貨車的都喜歡他  有好貨的時候
Drivers loved him. They used to tip him off...
他們都會把消息告訴他  當然  每個人都得到好處
about the really good loads. Of course, everybody got a piece.
謝了  我等下再來拿剩下的煙
Thanks, I'll be back for the rest later.
好吧  一會兒見
Okay, see you later.
亨利  到這裏來
Henry, come here.
- 跟湯米打個招呼  - 你好嗎  亨利
- Say hello to Tommy. - How're you doing, Henry?
你們好好的一起工作  好嗎
You're gonna be working together, okay?
儘管幫他
Help him. Go ahead.
吉米  偷到什麼好東西了嗎
Jimmy, you got anything good?
警察曾經派出大軍來捉吉米  他怎麼做
And when the cops assigned a whole army to stop Jimmy, what did he do?
他把他們變成了同夥
He made them partners.
想抱怨也沒人會聽
I'd complain, but who'd listen?
- 一條帕爾瑪爾  - 來
- One Pall Mall. - There you go.
- 你要什麼  - 我要兩條幸運紅圈
- What do you need? - Two Luckies.
- 來  亨利  - 真多謝  要什麼
- Here you go, Henry. - Thanks a lot... What do you need?
- 一條帕爾瑪爾  - 一條帕爾瑪爾  來
- One Pall Mall. - One Pall Mall, here you go.
- 你幹什麼  - 沒有  沒什麼事
- What are you doing? - It's all right.
- 你有你媽的許可嗎  - 你要幾條煙呀
- You have permission from your mother? - How many cartons you need?
- 你從哪裏弄來的香煙  - 把他弄走
- Where'd you get the cigarettes? - Get him out of here.
- 沒關係的  - 有關係
- It's okay. - It's not okay.
- 你不明白  - 是你不明白  店關了
- You don't understand. - You don't understand. Store's closed.
- 亨利被捕了  - 在哪被捕
- Henry got pinched. - Where?
在工廠那裏  他在賣煙
By the factory, selling cigarettes.
亨利·希爾  紐約州控訴亨利·希爾
Henry Hill. The People of the State of New York vs. Henry Hill.
案號704162
Docket number 704162.
是的  法官  我就是
Yes, sir. That's me.
走過來  站在那別動
Just stand there. Now stay there.
律師  繼續吧
Counselor, proceed.
恭喜
Congratulations.
這是你的畢業禮物
Here's your graduation present.
- 為什麼  我被捕了  - 每個人都會被捕  但你表現得很好
- What for? I got pinched. - Everyone does, but you did it right.
你什麼也沒說  他們也沒得到線索
You told them nothing, and they got nothing.
- 我以為你會生氣  - 我沒生你的氣  我為你驕傲
- I thought you'd be mad. - I'm not mad, I'm proud of you.
你初次被捕表現如男子漢  也學會了人生中最重要的兩件事
You took your first pinch like a man and learned the two greatest things in life.
- 是什麼  - 看著我
- What? - Look at me.
絕不背叛你的朋友
Never rat on your friends...
還有永不洩漏任何秘密
and always keep your mouth shut.
他來了
Here he is.
你有了第一次了
You broke your cherry.
恭喜你
Congratulations!
艾得偉機場  1963年
到我長大  每年從艾得偉機場
By the time I grew up, there was $30 billion a year in cargo...
進出的貨值300億
moving through Idlewild Airport...
你信不信  我們試圖把它偷光
and believe me, we tried to steal every bit of it.
我們是在機場旁邊混大的
See, you gotta understand, we grew up near the airport.
機場是屬於保利的
It belonged to Paulie.
我們有親戚朋友在各部門工作
We had friends and relatives who worked all over the place.
他們會告訴我們貨物進出的消息
They would tip us off about what was coming in and moving out.
假如有航空公司或是卡車司機找我們麻煩
If any truckers or airlines gave us trouble...
保利和他的工會人員就以罷工嚇他們  棒極了
Paulie had the union people scare them with a strike. It was beautiful.
這比彩票還賺  吉米就是管這檔事的
It was a bigger moneymaker than numbers and Jimmy was in charge of it all.
我們一需要錢就搶機場
Whenever we needed money, we'd rob the airport.
比搶花旗銀行還牛
To us, it was better than Citibank.
你有電話嗎  快呀
You got a phone? Come on!
兩個黑鬼偷了我的卡車  你相信這種事嗎
Two niggers just stole my truck. Can you believe that shit?
吉米
There was Jimmy...
跟湯米還有我
and Tommy and me.
還有安東尼·史提保
And there was Anthony Stabile.
近來怎麼樣
How're you doing?
法蘭克·卡本
Frankie Carbone.
還有毛黑的哥哥  肥佬安迪
And then there was Mo Black's brother, Fat Andy.
還有他的手下  意大利佬法蘭基
And his guys, Frankie the Wop.
還有沒鼻子佛萊迪
Freddy No Nose.
還有劊子手彼得  他是救世波爾的兄弟
And then there was Pete the Killer, who was Sally Balls'brother.
又有犀利眼尼基
Then you had Nickey Eyes...
還有米奇·法斯
and Mikey Franzese.
是呀  我想見他
That guy, I wanna see him.
還有由於什麼話都說兩遍而命名的二次奇米
Jimmy Two Times, who got that nickname because he said everything twice.
我要去拿報紙  拿報紙
I'm gonna go get the papers, get the papers.
這是什麼  大衣  亨利  我要西裝呀
What is this? Coats? Henry, I need suits, not coats.
西裝呀  禮拜四會到
Suits are coming Thursday.
可是現在是夏天  你叫我怎麼處理毛皮
But it's the middle of summer. What'll I do with fur coats?
你不要毛皮  那我把毛皮拿走
You don't want furs? I'll take them away.
不要拿走  我要用  我們把它們跟肉一起掛在冷凍庫裏
No, I want them. We'll hang them in the freezer with the meat. How's that?
要我們改變生活方式是不可能的
For us, to live any other way was nuts.
要我們跟那些老好人一樣找份爛工作  錢又少
To us, those goody-good people who worked shitty jobs for bum paychecks...
每天擠地下鐵上下班  帳單一大堆  不如死掉
and took the subway to work every day and worried about bills, were dead.
那些都是沒勇氣的弱者
They were suckers. They had no balls.
假如我們想要什麼  我們就拿
If we wanted something, we just took it.
任何人敢抱怨兩次以上  會被揍得不敢再抱怨第三次了
If anyone complained twice, they got hit so bad they never complained again.
一切都好像順理成章  根本不用多傷腦筋
It was just all routine. You didn't even think about it.
520和469有什麼關係
Frankie, what the fuck does 520 have to do with 469?
真不相信有這種人
I can't believe this guy.
520和469根本差太遠了
520 ain't even close to 469. What's that got to do with anything?
簡單得很  萬事俱備
Piece of cake. It's all there.
不用擔心警鈴  我在想辦法把鑰匙弄到手
Don't worry about the alarms. I just gotta find a way to get the key.
- 不會有問題吧  - 我會把事弄妥的
- No problem, right? - I'll take care of it.
- 把你告訴我的事告訴他  - 好得難以置信
- Tell him what you were telling me. - Too good to be true.
法國航空公司有大生意了  有一袋袋的錢要托運
Big score coming from Air France. Bags of money coming in.
美國的觀光客和軍人  他們把美金換成法郎
Tourists and American servicemen change their money...
美金又被運回來
into French money and send it back here.
- 冷靜一點  - 太美了
- Calm down. - It's beautiful.
完全無法追蹤
It's totally untraceable. Okay?
唯一的問題就是怎麼拿到鑰匙  但我已經想到辦法了
The only problem is getting a key, but I've got a plan.
- 我和法國佬和這個國民  - 這笨蛋很容易操縱的
- Me and Frenchy and this citizen. - Yeah, he's a piece of work.
假如我估計正確  那裏有50萬現金
If I'm right, there could be $500,000 coming in, all cash.
他說最好在週末下手  也許禮拜六晚上
The best time is probably over a weekend. So maybe Saturday night.
禮拜一是猶太教假日
There's a Jewish holiday on Monday.
要到禮拜二才會被發現  太美了
They won't find out until Tuesday. Beautiful.
警衛怎麼辦
What about the security?
警衛嗎
Security?
這位就是  笑死了  我就是午夜到早上八點的班
You're looking at it. It's a joke. I'm the midnight-to-eight man.
我就是總司令
I'm the commandant.
他就像來招領失物一樣就行了
He just comes in like he's picking up lost baggage.
- 太美了  - 不會出任何問題的
- It's beautiful. - It won't be a problem at all.
- 好  - 就這麼辦
- Good. - We're on.
最可笑的是在席考克斯搶銀行那一次
What's really funny is that fucking bank job in Secaucus.
我正躺在草裏
I'm in the middle of the weeds, lying down.
警察走過來問我  你在幹什麼
He says, "What are you doing?"
我說  我在休息呀
I said, "I'm resting."
這不是公園或海灘  我說  我在休息
"Here? This ain't no beach or park." I said, "I'm resting."
他們把我捉進去問東問西
He pulls me in, starts asking questions. You know, this and that.
你要告訴我們些什麼呢  我說  一如往常  零
"What are you going to tell us?" I said, "My usual. Nothing."
為什麼要告訴你  干  他說  今天你非說不可
"Why tell you?" The fuck. He says, "No, you'll tell me something today."
我說  那好  你去操你媽吧
I said, "Okay, go fuck your mother."
你看報紙了沒有  安東尼  我的頭腫得這麼大
You saw the paper, Anthony. My head was out like this.
當我醒過來
Now I'm coming around, and who do I see in front of me?
這死傢伙又站在我面前  你現在還有什麼話說
This prick again. He says, "What do you want to tell me now?"
你在這兒幹嘛  我不是叫你去操你媽嗎
I said, "What are you doing here? I told you to go fuck your mother."
我以為他會拉在褲子裏
I thought he was gonna shit.
我又被揍了一頓  那時候我真希望我是個大個子
The fuckers. I wish I was big just once.
真好玩  真滑稽
Funny. You're really funny.
你是什麼意思
What do you mean, I'm funny?
就是好玩  我是說你的故事很搞笑
It's funny, you know. It's a good story.
你很幽默
You're a funny guy.
你說我講話的樣子嗎
You mean the way I talk? What?
只是  你很有趣
It's just, you know. You're just funny.
你講事情經過的樣子  很有趣
You know, the way you tell the story and everything.
滑稽  好玩  有什麼好玩
Funny how? What's funny about it?
- 湯米  你誤會了  - 安東尼
- Tommy, you got it all wrong. - Anthony.
他又不是小孩子  讓他自己解釋  到底怎麼有趣法
He's a big boy. He knows what he said. What did you say?
只是  你就是很有趣嘛
Just, you know. You're funny.
讓我把事情弄清楚
Let me understand this.
也許我有點醉了
Maybe I'm a little fucked up.
但我是怎麼個有趣法  像小丑一樣嗎
But, I'm funny, how? Funny like a clown? I amuse you?
我是來逗你開心的嗎
I make you laugh? I'm here to fucking amuse you?
我到底是哪裏滑稽
What do you mean, funny? How am I funny?
你也知道嘛  就是你講故事的方式
You know, how you tell a story.
不  我不懂  是你說的
No, I don't know. You said it. How do I know? You said I'm funny.
我到底是哪裏滑稽
How the fuck am I funny? What the fuck is so funny about me?
我哪裏有趣  告訴我呀
Tell me what's funny.
你有完沒完呀  湯米
Get the fuck out of here, Tommy.
他媽的  他差點被我唬住了
Motherfucker! I almost had him!
你這個講話結巴的死傢伙  你
You stuttering prick, you!
法蘭基  他有沒有發抖
Frankie, was he shaking?
我真擔心你  亨利  你經不起拷問
I wonder about you sometimes, Henry. You may fold under questioning.
耶穌基督啊
Jesus Christ.
你在搞什麼呀  我還以為我被捕了
What the fuck is it with you? I thought I was getting pinched already.
他靠著我脖子  好像禿鷹一樣  你要什麼
He's hanging on my fucking neck like a vulture. What do you want?
夥計他說不敢把帳單拿過來給你
This guy didn't want to come and give you the check.
你能不能結一下帳
Could you take care of this?
沒問題  叫他記在我帳上
No problem. Tell him to put it on my tab. Of course.
我就是想跟你商量一下
That's what I want to talk to you about.
你的帳不只這些  你還欠我七千
It ain't just this one. It's seven big ones you owe me.
已經到七千塊了  不是小數目  我也不想失禮
$7,000, that ain't peanuts. I don't mean to be out of order...
你不想失禮
Don't mean to be out of order?
好在你不想失禮
It's good you don't mean to be out of order.
在我朋友面前說我賴帳
Embarrassing me in front of my friends, like I'm a deadbeat.
你知道嗎  桑尼  你真他媽的夠賤的
You know, Sonny, you're a fucking mutt.
我們在你這裏消費了多少
You know the money we spend in this fucking...
- 別這樣嘛  - 什麼別這樣
- Don't be like that. - What do you mean?
世界上真有這種人  你覺得這個有趣嗎
Do you believe this prick? You think this is funny?
你他媽的看什麼  你這個白癡
What the fuck are you looking at? You fucking moron!
你不願意拿帳單給我是不是
You don't want to bring the check?
真有這種人
Do you believe this prick?
你也應該對他們狠一點
You're supposed to be doing this stuff, too.
你真有意思
You're a funny guy.
- 這次你完了  亨利  - 不要這樣  坐下
- That's it, Henry. - No, go back.
你想笑嗎  這混蛋上禮拜還叫我給他兒子洗禮呢
You want to laugh? This prick last week asked me to christen his kid.
我就算他七千塊吧
I charged him $7,000.
你真笑死我了
You really are a funny guy.
我很擔心  我聽到些奇奇怪怪的事
I'm worried. I'm hearing all kinds of fucking bad things.
湯米對待我的方式就好像我是什麼怪物  同性戀似的
He's treating me like I'm a fucking fag.
我沒辦法逃避他
I got to go on the lam in order to get away from this guy.
他這樣是不對的  我沒地方好去
This ain't right. I can't go here, I can't go there.
不是只有你  我跟兄弟們說了很多次了  他們不聽
You think you're the only one? I talk to them, they don't listen.
假如你跟他說  他會聽的
If you tell him, he'll stop. I'll wind up being declared an MIA.
否則我會被發現死在後車廂或草叢裏
They'll find me in the back of a car somewhere in the weeds.
沒人比你更清楚湯米
You've known this Tommy all your life. Who knows better?
這傢伙是終極罪犯
This cocksucker's an arch criminal.
我每天出門的時候都擔心會遭暗算
When I leave my house, before I get to the car I look over both shoulders.
我沒法活下去了
This is no way to live. I'm no fence jumper.
我跟了你一輩子  你說我該怎麼辦
I'm around you all my life, tell me what I gotta do.
- 我必須怎麼做  就怎麼做  - 我能做什麼呢
- Whatever I got to do, I'm gonna do. - What could I do?
如果我能幫上忙  我一定會做的
If there was something I could do, I would. I would like to help you out.
桑尼  告訴他我們談的事
Sonny, tell him what we talked about.
- 你覺得妥當嗎  - 說吧
- You think it's all right? - Yeah.
我希望你成為我店裏的股東之一  那就好了
Maybe you could come in with me, take a piece of this joint. It'd be good.
你在說什麼  你是說餐廳
What are you talking about? You mean the restaurant?
那是個高級地方
It's a classy place. Look at the layout.
你去過很多次了
You've been in there a million times. You know how it looks.
如果湯米接去做  簡直像給豬戴絲帽一樣
Tommy taking over this joint is like putting a silk hat on a pig.
我不是看不起他  事實是如此
I don't mean no disrespect, but that's the way it is.
我還能說什麼  我是在求你
I know you're his friend. I'm begging you. What can I say?
我能做什麼
What am I gonna do? What do you want from me?
我對餐廳一竅不通
I don't know anything about the restaurant business. Nothing.
我只會點菜而已
All I know is to sit down and order a meal, not how to make a restaurant.
不是要你去管理  你只是多一個地方走動而已
Not for you. It's just a place to hang.
那裏的廚師很棒  表演也很好  漂亮小妞也多
The chef is great. The shows are good. There's a lot of whores coming in.
我真的很願意幫你  你要我怎麼做
I'd love to help you, but what do you want from me? What'll I do?
湯米是夠壞的  難道要我槍斃他
Tommy's a bad kid, a bad seed. What am I supposed to do? Shoot him?
這倒不是個壞主意
That wouldn't be a bad idea.
對不起  我不是真心的  只是他令我害怕
I'm sorry I said that. I didn't mean it. I just mean that he's scaring me.
我需要你的幫忙  求求你
I just need help. Help me, please.
餐廳生意你懂嗎
You know anything about this restaurant business?
他什麼都懂  他從早到晚都在那裏
He knows everything. He's there 24 hours a day.
他就像那裏的椅子一樣
Another fucking few minutes, he could be a stool.
永遠都在裏面
That's how often he's in there.
你要我做你的股東  搞了半天就是要我做你的股東是嗎
You want me to be your partner? Is that what you're telling me?
你以為我在說什麼  好不好  保利
What the fuck you think I'm talking about? Paulie, please. Come on.
那太不公平了
It's not even fair.
別這麼說
You don't understand.
好吧  你管理  我來從旁協助
You run the joint. Maybe I'll try to help you, all right.
上帝保佑你  保利  我真的很感激你  你對我真好
God bless you, Paulie. I appreciate it. You've always been fair with me.
現在桑尼有保利撐腰了  發生任何問題他都找保利
Now the guy's got Paulie as a partner. Any problems, he goes to Paulie.
有人不付錢  他就找保利
Trouble with a bill, he can go to Paulie.
警察  送貨的  甚至湯米給他找麻煩
Trouble with the cops, deliveries, Tommy...
他都能去找保利
he can call Paulie.
可是現在他每星期得付保利保護費
Now the guy's gotta come up with Paulie's money every week...
無論狀況如何
no matter what.
生意不好嗎  去你的  付錢  店失火啦  去你的  付錢
"Business is bad? Fuck you, pay me. Had a fire? Fuck you, pay me.
店被雷擊中啦  去你的  付錢
"The place got hit by lightning? Fuck you, pay me."
電視機給我一台好不好
Can I get one of those TVs?
保利可以為所欲為
Also, Paulie could do anything.
特別是拿餐廳的信貸到處消費
Especially run up bills on the joint's credit. And why not?
反正不準備付錢的
Nobody's gonna pay for it anyway.
貨一旦從前門進
When deliveries are made at the front door...
就送出後門廉價拍賣
you move the stuff out the back and sell it at a discount.
二百塊的一箱酒一百塊賣出去
You take a $200 case of booze and sell it for $100.
也不要緊  反正都是淨賺
It doesn't matter. It's all profit.
到最後
Then finally, when there's nothing left...
真他媽夠可惜了
Fucking shame.
別人不再借錢給你  廠商也不再送貨了
...when you can't borrow another buck or buy another case of booze...
你只好點根火柴把店燒了  領保險金
you bust the joint out. You light a match.
有什麼夠不到的  需要我幫你嗎
Do you need help reaching anything?
你像在裝飾一顆聖誕樹一樣
You look like you're decorating a Christmas tree.
你根本什麼都不會
You don't know what you're doing.
她是從富人區來的
She's from the Five Towns.
誰呀
Who?
那個猶太馬子  戴安  我想跟她上床
The Jew broad, Diane, I was telling you I'm going to shag.
我已經試了一個月了
I've been trying to bang her for a fucking month now.
問題就是她從不肯跟我單獨約會
She won't go out with me alone.
- 不  - 什麼不
- No. - No, what?
不什麼  我又沒請你
No, what? Who the fuck asked you anything?
我又沒問你  至少聽我說完好不好
I didn't ask you. Hear what I'm going to say.
好啦  什麼啦
All right, what?
好啦  是這樣
Okay, what.
她不肯跟意大利人出去
She don't want to go out with Italians alone.
她對意大利人有偏見
She's prejudiced against Italians.
什麼時候了  還有這種事
You fucking believe that? In this day and age?
這是什麼世界啊
What the fuck is this world coming to?
難以相信  一個猶太馬子對意大利人有偏見
I can't believe this. A Jew broad, prejudiced against Italians.
除非和她的女朋友一起  她絕不單獨跟我約會
She won't go out with me alone unless her girlfriend comes with us.
所以我想你可以當她女朋友的伴
So you come along, go out with her girlfriend.
看吧  我就知道
See? I knew it.
你知道什麼  有什麼不好
You knew what? What the fuck is wrong with that?
- 什麼時候  - 明天晚上
- When is this? - Tomorrow night.
明晚不行  我要見杜迪
I can't, I gotta meet Tuddy.
你可以早點出來  事後再去見杜迪
You could meet Tuddy. You can come early and then still go.
- 你怎麼老是這樣  - 別找理由了
- Why do you always do this? - Don't give me that shit.
我是找你幫忙
What did I ask you for? I'm asking you for a favor.
我幫過你不少忙的
I do a lot of fucking favors for you.
我想搞那娘們  你懂不懂
I'm trying to bang this fucking broad. Help me out.
她真的很漂亮
I don't understand you. She's beautiful!
住在高級區  這些猶太女孩很有錢
Her fucking family lives in the Five Towns. These Jews got money.
說不定整條街都是她家的  你也許會中頭獎也不一定
Maybe the family owns the whole block. You may wind up with a big score.
光聽你講猶太女朋友好了
You with your fucking mouth.
我約了杜迪十一點見  現在我正在給湯米做搭檔
I had a meeting with Tuddy at 11:00, and here I am, a backup guy for Tommy.
你吃飽了嗎
How about it? Did you have enough to eat?
很好吃  我正在節食
It was delicious. I'm just watching my diet.
讓我替你注意身材就好了
Let me watch your figure.
我等不及離開
I couldn't wait to get away.
他們還在吃主菜  我就已經叫點心了
I was ordering the dessert when they were eating dinner.
他們還在喝咖啡  我就先結帳了
When they were having coffee, I was asking for a check.
我有事情
I had business.
喝點咖啡吧  會清醒一點
Have some coffee. It'll wake you up.
- 帳單給我  - 你急什麼呀
- Can we have the check? - What are you doing?
- 我得走了  - 我們才剛到
- I got to go. - We just got here.
我還有事  我要走了
I got that thing. I gotta go.
再等幾分鐘  我們一起離開好嗎
Wait a couple of minutes. We'll leave together.
這樣才不會像一群流浪漢  一個一個走
This way we don't go out like a bunch of hobos, one at a time.
我受不了他
I couldn't stand him.
我覺得他真的很倒胃口
I thought he was really obnoxious.
四肢一直擺弄著
He kept fidgeting around.
可不可以不要玩打火機  很煩
You don't mind, do you? That's very annoying.
也許甜酒比較適合你  但我喝就不像樣了
Good? You might prefer Manischewitz, but it'd look funny on my table.
- 可以走了吧  - 亨利  放鬆一點嘛
- Ready? - Henry, lighten up.
我們才剛到  別緊張  好不好
We just got here. What are you doing?
回家的時候還沒到  他就把我推進車門
Before it was time to go home, he was pushing me into the car...
又拉了出來  太荒唐了
then pulling me out. It was ridiculous.
戴安和湯米
Diane and Tommy made us promise...
又約我們星期五見
to meet them again on Friday night.
我們答應了
We agreed.
果不其然  星期五晚上亨利沒來
Of course, when Friday night came around, Henry stood me up.
真抱歉  我不知道他在哪
I feel terrible. I don't know where he is.
可是他真的很喜歡你  他一直不停地談她
He really liked you, too. All he did was talk about her.
那天約會之夜只有我們三個人
We were a trio instead of a double date that night.
他該來通電話  我真擔心  希望不是太嚴重
He would have called. I hope it's nothing serious.
我逼湯米帶我去找他
But I made Tommy take me looking for him.
湯米  你搞什麼
Tommy, what the fuck?
你真有種呀  跟我爽約
You got some nerve standing me up.
從來沒有人敢這樣對我
Nobody does that to me.
你以為你是誰  像法蘭奇·瓦利那樣的大歌星嗎
Who do you think you are, Frankie Valli or some kind of big shot?
慢著好不好  我忘了  我以為是下星期
Slow down, I forgot. I thought it was next week.
是這個星期五  你答應的  你這個騙子
It was this Friday and you agreed, so you're a liar!
別這樣  別這樣  我們好好談一下
We can talk about this. Take it easy.
有什麼好談的
Talk about it?
去你的吧  我們沒什麼好談的
Talk to you after what you just did to me? Forget it.
我以為你不會來的  你那天什麼也不說  一副無聊的樣子
I thought you would stand me up. You looked bored. You didn't say anything.
再給我一次補償的機會吧
Let me make it up to you.
讓我考慮一下
I'll think about it.
我記得她在街上大喊大叫
I remember, she was screaming on the street, and I mean loud.
可是看起來真動人
But she looked good.
我會考慮考慮  不過有代價的  希爾
I'll think about it. But it'll cost you, Hill. A lot.
她的眼睛真美  就像伊莉莎白·泰勒（好萊塢女星）一樣
She had these great eyes just like Liz Taylor's.
至少我這麼覺得
At least that's what I thought.
哈羅  亨利
Hello, Henry.
- 你準備好了嗎  - 好了
- You're ready? - Yeah.
那走吧
Come on.
- 不  等一下  - 什麼
- No, wait a minute. - What?
快  把十字架蓋起來  我媽看到她會認為你是基督徒（猶太人不信基督教）
Quick, you have to cover that cross. My mother sees that...
凱倫
Karen.
媽
Mom.
- 這是我朋友亨利·希爾  - 你好嗎
- I'd like you to meet my friend, Henry Hill. - How do you do?
我女兒說你是半個猶太人
My daughter says that you're half Jewish.
好的一半是
It's just the good half.
- 謝謝  先生  - 謝謝
- Thank you, sir. - Bye, see you later, thanks.
你幹嘛把車停在這裏
What're you doing? You're leaving your car?
他會替我看著
He watches the car for me.
比停在停車場快多了
It's easier than leaving it at a garage and waiting.
這樣快多了  懂我意思嗎
It's a lot quicker that way, you know what I mean?
我喜歡從這裏走  比排隊好
I like going in this way. It's better than waiting in line.
你好  一切都好吧  這給你
How are you doing? What's up? Here you go.
- 你好嗎  - 你好
- How are you doing? - I'm doing all right.
我每次來  你們兩個都在這裏  不用工作嗎
Every time I come here, every time, you two. Don't you work?
你好嗎  嗨  你好嗎
Henry, nice to see you. Hi, how are you?
安東尼  擺在最前面
Anthony, right in the front.
如果需要什麼  告訴我就好了
Anything you need, just let me know.
東尼  真是謝了  我很感激
Tony, thanks a lot. I appreciate it.
- 你給他們每人二十塊錢  - 沒關係的
- You gave them $20 each. - It's all right.
亨利  這是東尼先生送的
Henry, this is with Mr. Tony, over there.
- 在哪裏  - 就在這邊
- Where? - Over there.
謝了  東尼
Thanks a lot, Tony.
- 你靠什麼生活  - 什麼
- What do you do? - What?
- 你靠什麼生活  - 我在建築界
- What do you do? - I'm in construction.
這雙手不像做建築的
They don't feel like you're in construction.
我是工會代表
I'm a union delegate.
各位女士  先生
Now, ladies and gentlemen...
很榮幸為各位介紹單句笑話之王
the Copacabana is proud to present the king of one-liners...
亨利·洋曼
Henny Youngman.
各位好  我能在這裏表演感到驕傲  請把我太太帶走
How are you all? I'm glad to be here. Take my wife, please.
不論我把我太太丟在什麼地方  她總會回家
I take my wife everywhere but she finds her way home.
我問她要去哪裏慶祝結婚紀念
I said, "Where do you wanna go for our anniversary?"
她說要到一個她從來沒去過的地方
She said, "Somewhere I've never been before."
我說  那就去廚房好了
I said, "Try the kitchen."
韋士勒醫生在場
Dr. Wellsler is here.
給病人估計還能活六個月  時候到了卻繳不出來醫藥費
Gave a guy six months to live. Couldn't pay his bill.
他又告訴病人還能再活六個月
Gave him another six months.
我真喜歡你們
I love this crowd.
非工作人員止步
是法國航空讓我成功的
Air France made me.
連槍都沒有用就搶走了42萬
We walked out with $420,000 without using a gun.
當然也給了保利他應得的保護費
And we did the right thing. We gave Paulie his tribute.
6萬元
$60,000.
我們會過一個好夏天
It's going to be a good summer.
我為你驕傲  對你這個年紀  那是筆大數目
I'm proud of you. That is a lot of money for a kid like you.
任何人問起來  就說是在賭城贏的
Anybody asks you where you got it, you got it in Vegas playing craps, all right?
好的
All right.
先生  帳單
Check, sir.
別拿大票子  在這裏是用簽名的
No. You have to sign for it here.
要不要給他小費
Should I tip him?
- 你好嗎  - 很好  你呢
- How are you doing? - Okay. How are you?
亨利  這是布魯斯  布魯斯  這是亨利
Henry, this is Bruce. Bruce, this is Henry.
你好嗎
Good to meet you.
有機會再聚
I'll see you around later.
- 你認識他嗎  - 是呀
- Do you know him? - Yeah.
住我家對面
He lives across the street.
有一天晚上  巴比·雲頓送我們無比可口的香檳酒
One night, Bobby Vinton sent us champagne. There was nothing like it.
一個21歲的年輕人有這樣的關係
I didn't think there was anything strange in any of this.
我並不感到奇怪
A 21-year-old kid with such connections.
跟他在一起很刺激
He was an exciting guy.
他對我很好  把我介紹給他所有的朋友
He was really nice. He introduced me to everybody.
每個人都對他很好
Everybody wanted to be nice to him.
他也應對得很得體
He knew how to handle it.
不要買會掉下來的假髮
Don't buy wigs that come off at the wrong time.
摩裏的假髮不會掉下來
Morrie's wigs don't come off!
在水中也沒事
Even underwater.
在狂風中也安然無恙
And remember, Morrie's wigs are tested against hurricane winds.
別擔心價錢  價錢不是問題
Forget about money. You can afford a Morrie wig. Priced to fit every budget.
來電話
Call me now!
約時間試試看吧
Come in for a personalized fitting.
走呀  摩裏  吉米在等著  你欠的錢已經過期了
Come on, Morrie. Jimmy's waiting. You're past due.
你這個人不錯  我對你不錯  你對我也不錯
You're a good kid. We've been good to each other.
但有些事不合理
But there's something unreasonable going on here.
吉米太狠了
Jimmy's being a ball-breaker.
我賭克裏夫蘭隊  下注8:5
Give him 8-to-5 on Cleveland.
我沒法付那麼高的利息
I never had to pay the vigorish he demands. Am I something special?
你以為我是什麼  白癡呀
What am I, a schmuck on wheels?
你向吉米借了錢  你就該還給他
You know Jimmy. You borrowed his money. Pay him.
我沒同意高利之外又加三分
I didn't agree to three points above the vig.
你要怎麼樣嘛  你要對付吉米嗎
What are you going to do? Fight with Jimmy Conway?
他要他的錢  你付了錢  我好走路呀
He wants his money. Give him his money and we'll go.
去他的吧
Fuck him!
操他耳朵啦  操他另外一隻耳朵
Fuck him in the ear! Fuck him in the other ear!
我有沒有給他出過漏子
Did I ever bust his balls? Did I?
我只要一通電話給條子  我就什麼錢也不用付了
I could've dropped a dime a million times.
別發瘋了  好不好
You're talking crazy. Stop it now, will you?
你有錢去做電視廣告
You got money for that fucking commercial.
沒錢還給我是吧
You don't got my money?
吉米  他會還給你的
Jimmy, he's gonna pay you.
我要宰了你  你這個奴才  錢拿給我
I'll fucking kill you. Give me the money, cocksucker.
把錢還我
Pay me my money.
他會付
He'll pay.
摩裏假髮  是誰  他在這兒
Morrie's. Who's this? He's here.
- 對不起  吉米  - 你應該對不起
- Jimmy, I'm sorry. - You should be sorry.
把錢還我  再有一次你就完了
Don't do it again. Give me the fucking money!
你聽著  把錢還給我
You hear me? Give me the fucking money.
我會給  我會給
I'll give you. You've got it, kid. You've got it, believe me.
凱倫  慢慢講嘛
Karen, slow down.
哪裏  就在那裏  不要走開
Where? Stay there. Don't move.
- 發生了什麼事  - 是凱倫  吉米
- What happened? - It's Karen, Jimmy.
- 今天就付  - 我會付
- Money today. - I'll pay.
發生了什麼事
What happened?
- 你還好嗎  - 我沒事
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
是誰幹的
Who did it?
住在我家對面  我從小就認識的一個傢伙
This guy who lives across the street from me that I've known all my life.
他開始摸我  抓我
He started to touch me. He stared to grab me.
我叫他住手  他不聽
I told him to stop. He didn't stop.
我就打他  結果他發火了
I hit him back. And then he got really angry.
把我推出車外
He pushed me out of the car.
你確定你沒事嗎
You sure you're all right?
你進去吧  整理一下  梳洗乾淨
Why don't you go inside and get yourself together. Clean up.
你想幹什麼  敗類  你想要什麼嗎
What do you want, fucko? You want something?
以我母親的名義發誓  你再碰凱倫一下  你就死定了
I swear on my fucking mother, if you touch her again, you're dead.
不要開槍
Don't shoot.
- 把槍藏起來  你沒事吧  - 沒事
- Hide this. Are you all right? - Yeah.
我知道  一般女孩一定會和男朋友分手
I know there are women, like my best friends...
如果她男朋友拿一支槍
who would have gotten out the minute their boyfriend...
叫她拿去藏起來  但我沒有
gave them a gun to hide. But I didn't.
老實說  我覺得這很刺激
I've got to admit the truth. It turned me on.
恭喜
Mazel tov!
你為什麼不學亨利  他就有個好姑娘在身邊
Why don't you be like your friend Henry? He's got a nice girl.
他要安定了  妻子都娶了
He's settling down now. He's married.
不久就有個小家庭了
Pretty soon he'll have a nice family.
你老是一個接一個的換
And you're still bouncing around from girl to girl.
亨利好像有兩個家庭
It was like he had two families.
他把他們介紹給我時真是多到瘋掉
The first time I was introduced to all of them at once, it was crazy.
保利和他的兄弟們都有一大堆孩子
Paulie and his brothers had lots of sons and nephews.
幾乎都叫彼德或保羅
Almost all of them were named Peter or Paul.
簡直不敢相信
It was unbelievable.
這位是我侄兒小保利  然後這是彼迪
Meet Paulie Jr., my nephew. And this is Petey.
婚禮中起碼有兩打以上的彼德和保羅
There must have been two dozen Peters and Pauls at the wedding.
這是瑪莉
This is Marie.
他們的妻子也都叫瑪莉
Plus, they were all married to girls named Marie.
- 看起來像意大利人  - 沒錯  她就是意大利人
- She looks Italian. - She is Italian, you're right.
他們的女兒也都叫瑪莉
And they named all their daughters Marie.
這是彼德  不  是保利  我有時也會弄錯
And this is Pete. No, I mean Paulie. I get confused myself.
當我和每個人打過招呼後  我以為我醉了
By the time I finished meeting everybody, I thought I was drunk.
保利  你太客氣了
Paulie, you shouldn't have.
歡迎你成為家庭中的一份子
Welcome to the family.
星期日來我家晚餐
Sunday dinner?
真漂亮  我真想哭
So beautiful. I want to cry.
小小意思  可以幫你們建立一個家庭
Here's something to help you get started.
- 那個袋子  那個袋子呢  - 什麼袋子
- The bag. The bag. - What? What bag?
那個裝滿了信封和錢的袋子呀
The bag with the envelopes in it, all the money.
別擔心  沒人會偷的
Don't worry about that. Nobody's going to steal that here.
他連電話都沒打
He didn't call?
- 他和朋友在一起  - 他是什麼人  連電話都不打
- He's with his friends. - What kind of person doesn't call?
媽  他是成人  不需要每五分鐘來一個電話
He's a grown-up. He doesn't have to call every five minutes.
如果是成人  為什麼不搬出去住
If he was such a grown-up why doesn't he get you two an apartment?
媽  是你要我們住在這裏的
Don't start. Mom, you're the one who wanted us here.
聽著  你在這裏一個月了  我知道他經常不回家
You're here a month and sometimes I know he doesn't come home at all.
他們到底是什麼樣的人
What kind of people are these?
- 媽  你要我怎麼樣  - 你能怎麼樣
- What do you want me to do? - Do? What can you do?
他又不是猶太人  你瞭解他們嗎
He's not Jewish. Did you know how these people live?
你爸爸可不是整夜不歸  電話也不打
Your father never stayed out all night without calling.
整夜不歸  爸爸連門都不出  媽  你少管我們
Stay out? Daddy never went out at all, Ma! Keep out of it.
你不明白我的感覺
You don't know how I feel!
你有什麼感覺
How do you feel now?
既不知道他在哪裏  也不知道他和什麼人在一起
You don't know where he is or who he's with.
他和朋友在一起  爸爸
He's with his friends! Dad!
不要把你爸爸扯進來
Leave him out of this. He's suffered enough.
他已經有六星期消化不良了
He hasn't digested a decent meal in six weeks.
你去了些什麼地方  為什麼不打電話
Where were you? Why didn't you call?
我們擔心死了  已婚男人不該整夜不歸
We were worried to death. A married man does not stay out like this.
正常人沒有這種行為的
Normal people don't act like this!
你哪裏不對勁
What's wrong with you?
她沒說錯  你是不正常  你哪裏不對勁
You're not normal. She's right. What's wrong with you?
你有什麼毛病  你是什麼樣的人
What kind of person are you? What is the matter with you?
他們那些傢伙是哪種人
What kind of people are they?
我們嫁的不是上班族
We weren't married to nine-to-five guys.
讓我感到有多不同
But the first time I realized how different...
是在美琪的家庭聚會時
was when Mickey had a hostess party.
- 凱倫  你是哪裏人  - 勞倫斯
- Karen, where you from? - Lawrence.
在長島  不錯呀  我生在邁阿密  你去過嗎
On the Island. It's nice. I'm from Miami. You ever been there?
那裏還不錯  像個猶太天堂
It's okay, but it's like you died and woke up in Jew heaven.
不要老擠痘子嘛
Angie, stop picking at that thing.
我真想揍他的臉
I'd like to smack his face.
那個紅髮男人
The red-haired guy, looks like a farmer?
他都要動手動腳的
The guy's hands are all over me.
我說  不要對我動手  否則我把它切下來
So I told him, "Keep your fucking hands off me, or I'll cut them off."
她是認真的
She means it.
他不知道多走運  如果我告訴韋力
You don't know how lucky he is. I just mention this to Vinnie...
你怎麼能告訴韋力  他非殺了他不可
How can you mention it? Vinnie would kill him.
說出來  韋力殺了他  又得去坐一輩子牢
If I don't, he'll kill the miserable bastard, then Vinnie will be there for life.
你以為只有你有麻煩呀  珍妮的兒子更糟
You think you got problems. What about Jeannie's kid?
在一場只有10元輸贏的撲克中和人爭執起來  他拿出槍
He was in an argument. A $10 card game. He pulls out a gun.
槍走火  打死一個男孩  當他祖母聽到他在牢裏
The gun goes off. Some kid gets killed. When the grandmother hears it...
心臟病發作  當場就死了
and finds out he's jailed, she has a heart attack and drops dead right on the spot.
現在珍妮的老公和孩子在牢裏  媽媽在殯儀館
Now Jeannie has a husband and son in jail and a mother in the funeral parlor.
- 珍妮酗酒  - 也許她是心情不好
- Jeannie drinks. - Maybe she's depressed.
饒了我吧  她根本就是酗酒
Give me a break. She's drunk.
只要有點事發生  他們都成聖人了
As soon as something happens, you make them out to be saints.
她們皮膚粗糙  化妝太濃  氣色不好
They had bad skin and wore too much makeup. They didn't look very good.
她們看起來很憔悴  穿的衣服
They looked beat-up. And the stuff they wore...
也是不成套的廉價品
was thrown together and cheap.
都是些褲裝  針織品
A lot of pantsuits and double-knits.
她晝夜穿睡袍
She spends her life in a nightgown.
相信我  她不是什麼好東西
The woman is no angel, believe me.
她們談論著她們的孩子多壞
They talked about their rotten kids...
她們用掃把揍孩子  她們用皮鞭揍孩子
and about beating them with broom handles and belts.
但孩子們一點也不理會
And that the kids still didn't pay any attention.
當亨利來接我的時候  我整個頭都暈了
When Henry picked me up, I was dizzy.
我不知道我能不能適應這種生活
I don't know if I could live like that.
你要是進了監牢  我怎麼辦
God forbid, what would happen if you had to go to prison?
凱倫
Karen.
美琪談到了珍妮的丈夫
Mickey said that Jeannie's husband...
你知道怎麼回事嗎
Do you know why Jeannie's husband went to the can?
珍妮的丈夫是為了逃避珍妮才去坐牢的
Because of Jeannie. He wanted to get away from her.
你聽我說  坐牢的都是想坐牢的
Let me tell you something. Nobody goes to jail unless they want to.
都是甘願被捕的
Unless they make themselves get caught.
他們沒把事情安排好
They don't have things organized.
我都把事弄妥了
I know what I'm doing. I've got things organized with these guys.
你知道哪些人坐牢嗎
You know who goes to jail?
黑人搶劫犯  你知道他們為什麼會被捕嗎
Nigger stickup men. You know why they get caught?
因為他們在逃走用的車上睡著了
Because they fall asleep in the getaway car, Karen.
凱倫  不要瞎擔心了  甜心  過來吧
Come on, don't worry so much, sweetie. Come here.
漸漸地  一切都好像很正常了
After a while, it got to be all normal.
沒有一樣像犯罪
None of it seemed like crime.
亨利就像在經營企業
It was more like Henry was enterprising...
他和夥伴以詐騙為生而已
and that he and the guys made bucks hustling while other guys...
至少他們不坐著等別人來救濟
were sitting on their asses waiting for handouts.
我們的丈夫不是腦外科醫生  他們是靠努力賺錢的
Our husbands weren't brain surgeons, they were blue-collar guys.
他們只有多偷  多搶  才能多賺點錢
The only way they could make real extra money was to go out and cut corners.
錢箱在那裏  討人厭的東西
Where's the strong box, you varmint?
你他媽的別動
Don't fucking move! Don't move.
- 餐廳見了  - 我坐副駕駛座
- See you at the diner. - I'm riding shotgun.
你看他剛才立刻就服軟了
Did you see him give it right over?
走吧  回老巢去分錢吧
Back to the hideout to split up the loot.
我們非常親近
We were all so very close.
從來不跟外人來往  絕不
There were never any outsiders around. Absolutely never.
就因為這樣  一切好像更正常了
Being together all the time made everything seem all the more normal.
哈羅  希爾太太  警察
Hello, Mrs. Hill. Police.
我是迪西警探  他是席維思警探  我們有搜查令
I'm Detective Deacy. This is Detective Silvestri. We have a search warrant.
請看一下  然後簽名
Would you read and sign it?
- 哪裏都行嗎  - 是的
- Anywhere? - Yeah, anywhere.
要耽誤一點時間  我們每樣都要仔細查
This'll take a while, we have to go through everything.
- 你們要咖啡嗎  - 不用了  謝謝你
- You boys want some coffee? - No coffee now, thanks.
- 請當心點  - 我們只是照常執行任務
- Be careful. - We'll just go about our business.
警察經常會找些小麻煩
There was always a little harassment.
他們要跟亨利談東談西
They wanted to talk to Henry about this or that.
他們帶著傳票和搜查令來叫我簽名
They'd make me sign their subpoenas or warrants.
不論他們搜到什麼
But mostly they just wanted a handout.
幾塊錢也就把他們打發了
A few bucks to keep things quiet no matter what they found.
我每次都問他們  要不要咖啡  有的太太  像美琪
I always asked if they wanted coffee. Some wives, like Mickey Conway...
她總是詛咒他們  還吐口水在地板上
used to curse at them and spit on the floor.
我永遠也不瞭解為什麼要吐在自己的地板上
She used to spit on her own floor. That never made any sense to me.
還是禮貌一點  然後打電話給律師比較好
It was better to be polite and call the lawyer.
我們總是在一起  總是同樣一群人
We always did everything together, and we always were in the same crowd.
紀念日  受洗等等  我們只到彼此的家去
Anniversaries, christenings. We only went to each other's houses.
女士們一起玩牌
The women played cards.
凡有嬰兒誕生  美琪和吉米總是最先到醫院的
When kids were born, Mickey and Jimmy were the first at the hospital.
當我們去南海或賭城度假
When we went to the Islands or Vegas for vacation...
也都是一起的
we went together.
從來沒有外人  好像那才是正常的
No outsiders ever. It got to be normal.
我甚至對我丈夫的所作所為
It got to where I was proud that I had the kind of husband...
感到驕傲
who was willing to risk his neck just to get us the little extras.
我已經跟媽講好了  明晚來替我們看孩子
But I got Mom to watch the babies tomorrow night.
- 我沒辦法  凱倫  - 為什麼
- Can't do it, Karen. - Why not?
就是不行嘛  我已安排好別的事了
I just can't. I got something lined up.
但媽媽只有明晚可以替我們看孩子
But tomorrow's the only night she can do it.
- 拜託嘛  好不好  - 我真的不行  你要我怎麼辦
- Pretty please? - I can't. What do you want me to do?
- 我得走了  - 等一下
- I got to go. - Wait a minute.
我要去逛街  給我點錢好嗎
I wanted to go shopping. Can I get some money?
你需要多少
How much do you need?
- 多少  - 這麼多
- How much? - That much.
這麼多  親我一下
This much. Give me a kiss.
待會見
See you later.
好吧
All right.
紐約皇后區  1970年6月11日
歡迎你回來
Welcome home, Batts.
近來好嗎?
Hi, how are you?
坐下  喝一杯  給每個人一杯酒
Sit down. Have a drink. Give them all a drink.
那些愛爾蘭流氓  也給他們一杯
And give those Irish hoodlums a drink.
只有一個愛爾蘭人
There's only one Irishman here.
這是慶祝會  乾杯
It's a celebration, fellas.
- 祝你早安  - 從牢裏回來真好
- Top of the morning to you. - It's good to be home.
這是我朋友吉米
This is my friend Jimmy.
這裏是亨利的店  這是莉莎
Henry. It's his joint. This is Lisa.
湯米  這麼盛裝呀
Tommy. All dressed up.
已經是大人了  你看看
All grown up and doing the town. Look at this.
忘了你們在替他慶祝
Forgot you were having a party for this mug.
過來呀
Come here.
我過去打個招呼  比利  你好嗎
I'll say hello. Billy, how are you?
我已經六年沒見你了
Get over here. I haven't seen you in six years.
上帝  你看起來真神氣
Jesus Christ Almighty. You look terrific.
當心我的西裝
Watch the suit.
你這小混球  我認識你一輩子了
You little prick. I've known you all my life.
- 不要長得太大了  - 你不要找我麻煩就好了
- Don't get too big on me. - Just don't bust my balls.
如果我要找你麻煩  我會叫你回去拿擦鞋盒來
If I was gonna break your balls, I'd say, "Go get your shine box."
這小鬼以前鞋擦得真亮
This kid was great.
他外號叫  亮光湯米
They used to call him "Spitshine Tommy."
他媽的簡直像鏡子一樣  語氣稍粗了  抱歉
He'd make your shoes look like fucking mirrors. Excuse my language.
他真賺了不少錢
He was terrific. He was the best. He made a lot of money, too.
不要再提擦鞋了  比利
No more shines, Billy.
- 什麼  - 我說不要再提擦鞋了
- What? - I said no more shines.
你離開了很長一段時間  他們沒告訴你
You've been away a long time. They didn't tell you.
我不擦鞋了
I don't shine shoes anymore.
不要這麼認真好不好  只是好玩的  給你找點小麻煩而已
Relax. What's got into you? I'm breaking your balls a little, that's all.
我只是逗著你玩的
I'm only kidding with you.
有時你的語氣不像在玩  這裏有很多人  你知道嗎
Sometimes you don't sound like it. There's a lot of people around.
我只是跟你開玩笑  我們在慶祝
I'm only kidding. We're having a party.
我好久沒見你  只想逗逗你  你馬上就變臉了
I haven't seen you in a long time and you get fucking fresh.
對不起  我不是故意想惹你生氣
I'm sorry, I didn't mean to offend you.
抱歉  沒事了  好了
I'm sorry, too. It's okay. No problem.
回去把你的擦鞋箱拿來
Now go home and get your fucking shine box.
你他媽的不是人養的
Motherfucking mutt!
你這攤大便
You fucking piece of shit!
來呀  來呀
Come on, come on!
誰不知道你用錢買到你在幫中的地位  假狠
He bought his fucking button! That fake old tough guy!
誰不知道你用錢買到你在幫中的地位
You bought your fucking button!
- 別緊張  - 你這個蓄生
- Don't get nervous. - You motherfucker!
把這王八蛋留在這裏
Keep that motherfucker here! Keep him here.
來呀  你以為你很強嗎
Come on, you fucking feel strong?
湯米喝太多了  他並沒惡意
Sorry. Tommy gets a little loaded. He doesn't mean any disrespect.
他沒有惡意  你瘋啦
He doesn't mean any disrespect? Are you nuts?
應該教這小子一點禮貌  對就是對
Teach this kid a little fucking manners. What's right is right.
- 你知道我的意思吧  - 沒關係
- You understand what I'm saying? - It's all right.
我是說那小子兩分鐘前還跟我行貼面禮  一轉臉就六親不認了
We're hugging and kissing over here and then he acts like a fucking jerk.
那是因為你諷刺他  你自己也有不對
You insulted him a little bit. You got a little out of order.
- 哪有  - 你有一點諷刺他
- I didn't. - You insulted him a little.
- 我沒諷刺任何人  給我們來酒  - 好的
- I didn't insult anybody. Give us a drink. - Okay.
我們都來一杯吧  我請客
Let's have some drinks. Drinks on the house.
不  由我來請
No, have the drink with me.
比利  酒免費
The drinks are on the house.
我在牢裏都強姦那種小子
I fucked kids like that in the can. In the ass.
他媽的  敢破壞我的慶祝會
Fucking break up my party.
時代變了  你離開六年了
You've been away for six years. It's different now.
我已經被懲罰過了
I did my fucking time, Jimmy.
我回來了  我要我該有的一份  我得養家餬口
I came home and I want what I got to get. I got mouths to feed.
- 你會得到的  - 你能瞭解吧
- You're gonna get it. - You understand?
關上門
Get the door!
讓我把子彈射進他的大爛嘴巴
Let me shoot him in his big, fucking mouth!
槍斃了他
Let's shoot him.
死傢伙把我鞋弄凹了
Fucking mutt dented my shoes.
他手下的人會到處找他的
His whole crew is going to be looking for him.
真糟糕  怎麼處理他  總不能把他丟在街上
This is bad. What do we do with him? We can't just dump him on the street.
我知道郊外有個地方  誰也找不到  再拿幾張桌布
I know a place upstate. They'll never find him. More tablecloths.
我本來不想把血濺在你地板上
I didn't want to get blood on your floor.
去把你的車廂打開
Go open your trunk.
到我媽媽家去拿一把鏟子
We'll get a shovel at my mother's house.
她有一把鏟子就放在附近  小聲一點  別把她吵醒
She has a shovel here somewhere. Quiet, I don't want to wake her up.
看誰來了
Look who's here.
你們剛才在做什麼  發生了什麼事
What did you do? What happened?
我在路上撞了一隻動物  吉米會告訴你
I hit something on the road. Jimmy will tell you.
發生什麼事了
What happened to him?
我好久沒看到你了  他怎麼啦
I haven't seen you in so long. What happened to him?
你好嗎
You, too. How are you?
你怎麼這麼晚還不睡
Why are you up so late?
他來了  你們都來了  我好高興看到他
He came in. You came in. I'm so happy to see him.
快進來吧  不要客氣  我給你們弄點吃的
Go inside. Make yourselves comfortable. I'll make you something to eat.
- 你去睡吧  - 我睡不著  我好久沒看到他了
- Go to sleep. We're leaving. - I can't. Not while he's home.
我好久沒看到他了  我想陪陪他
I haven't seen him in so long. I want to see him.
你們進去吧
You go inside.
This stuff is like lead.
告訴我  你去哪裏了  我都沒看見你
Tell me, where you been? I haven't seen you.
也不打個電話回來  你都去哪了
You haven't called. Where have you been?
- 我在上夜班  - 然後呢
- I been working nights. - And?
今晚我們開車到郊外溜達
And tonight we were out late.
撞上一隻鹿
We took a ride out to the country and hit a deer.
所以才有這些血  吉米不也告訴你了嗎
That's where all the blood is from. Jimmy told you.
對了  我要借這把刀用一下  好嗎
It reminds me, I need this knife. I'm taking this, okay?
- 用吧  - 我只需要用一下就好
- Okay. - Just for a while.
可憐的鹿
The poor thing.
我們撞到那隻鹿的  那個  那個叫什麼
We hit the deer and his paw... What do you call it?
前爪
The paw.
- 鹿蹄  - 他前蹄被卡住了
- The hoof. - Got caught in the grill.
我必須把它切下來
I got to hack it off.
如果不管它  那太不人道了
Ma, it's a sin to leave it there.
刀用完我就送回來
I'll bring the knife back.
- 真好吃  美味  - 謝謝你
- Delicious. - Thank you.
你為什麼不找個好姑娘
Why don't you get yourself a nice girl?
我每天晚上都找好姑娘
I do, almost every night.
我是說找個好女孩  能結婚安定下來
But get yourself a girl so you could settle down.
我每晚都安定下來  然後早上又自由了
I do, every night. Then I'm free.
我愛你  只想和你在一起
I love you, I want to be with you.
安定一下自己啦
Settle down.
亨利怎麼樣呀
How's your friend Henry?
怎麼了  你不怎麼講話
What's the matter? You don't talk much.
對啊  這麼安靜做什麼
Talk. What are you quiet for?
他吃得少  說話也少
You don't eat much, you don't talk much.
- 我聽著就好了  - 有什麼不對勁嗎
- I'm just listening. - Something wrong?
你讓我想起我們小的時候  從意大利來的人都很親近
When we were kids, the compares used to visit each other.
有一個人從來不說話  他整晚坐著一句話都不說
There was this man. He would never talk. He'd just sit there all night, not a word.
有人問他  你哪裏不對勁呀  你會不會說話
They say to him, "What's the matter? Don't you say anything?"
他說  你要我說什麼  說我老婆愛偷情
He says, "What am I going to say, that my wife two-times me?"
他老婆說  閉嘴  你話太多了
So she says, "Shut up! You're always talking."
不過這句話用意大利語說出來好聽多了
But in Italian, it sounds much nicer.
- 自得其樂  - 就是 滿於現況 的意思
- Cornuto contento. - That's it.
- 什麼意思呀  - 就是連那樣他都滿足
- What does that mean? - It means he's content to be a jerk.
別人怎麼想  他才不在乎
He doesn't care who knows it.
- 湯米有沒有告訴你們我畫畫  - 沒有
- Did Tommy tell you about my painting? - No.
看看這個
Look at this.
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
一隻狗臉朝這邊  另一隻臉朝那邊
I like it. One dog goes one way and the other goes the other.
一隻想到東部  一隻想到西部  又怎樣咧
One's facing east, the other west. So what?
這人在說  你要我怎麼樣  他那頭白髮挺漂亮的
He's saying, "What do you want from me?" The guy's got nice white hair.
漂亮  那隻狗  看起來差不多
Beautiful. The dog looks the same.
這個人有點像我們認識的一個人
Looks like somebody we know.
去掉鬍子不就是他嗎
Without the beard. It's him.
就是他
It's him.
媽的  什麼聲音啊
What the fuck is that?
對大部分兄弟來說  殺人是被接受的
For most of the guys, killings were accepted.
要令每個人服從  只有用處決來控制
Murder was the only way everybody stayed in line.
你如果越軌就會被除掉  規則大家都知道
You got out of line, you got whacked. Everybody knew the rules.
有時候沒越軌也會被除掉
Sometimes, even if people didn't get out of line, they got whacked.
有些兄弟已是殺人成性  動不動就挑釁
Hits became a habit. Guys would get into arguments over nothing.
時常  轉眼就死了一個人
Before you knew it, one was dead.
彼此常以槍相對
They were shooting each other all the time.
早已習以為常  不值得大驚小怪
Shooting people was a normal thing. It was no big deal.
我們跟比利·貝茲的事可不是件小事情
We had a serious problem with Billy Batts.
湯米殺的是個大人物  地位很高的
This was really a touchy thing. Tommy killed a made guy.
貝茲是坎必諾家族的一員  這種人是不能隨便殺的
Batts was part of the Gambino crew and was considered untouchable.
你得有充分的理由
Before you touched a made guy, you had to have a good reason.
你得有上面正式的許可
You had to have a sit-down and you'd better get an okay...
否則  被殺的人就是你
or you'd be the one who got whacked.
星期六是太太之夜
Saturday night was for wives...
禮拜五是女朋友之夜
but Friday night at the Copa was for the girlfriends.
上星期我們看了山米·戴維斯的秀
Last week, we saw Sammy Davis, Jr.
太值得看了  好會表演
You got to see this show. What a performer.
他會模仿別人  聽起來就跟真人一樣
He does these impersonations. You'd think it was the real people.
真令人難以相信  難怪白人女孩為他傾心
It's unbelievable. You could see how a white girl could fall for him.
什麼
What?
我不是說我  只是有的女孩  像那個瑞典女孩
Not me. But you could see how some girls could. Like that Swedish girl.
換句話說  你贊同那種黑白關係
So you condone that stuff.
別那麼認真
Take it easy.
我不要間接跟黑人接吻
I don't want to be kissing Nat King Cole over here.
我又不是在說我自己
No, I'm not talking about me.
他很有個性
But, you know, he's got personality.
個性
Personality?
他非常有才氣  我完全明白
He's talented. I understand what you're saying.
不過你要注意你所說的話  別人很容易誤會
But watch what you say. People get the wrong impression.
我只是說他很有才氣  令人難以相信
I just said he was talented, you're unbelievable.
你說夠了吧  你說的我都懂
Just leave it alone now, I understand what you said.
他很有才氣  就這樣子
He's talented. Leave it at that.
連給保利叔叔親一下都不行
No? Not even Uncle Paulie?
你有沒有聽到什麼消息
What did you hear about that thing?
- 布魯克林的事嗎  - 不是  城中那傢伙的事
- The Brooklyn thing? - No, the guy from downtown.
- 克莉絲家附近那傢伙嗎  - 不是
- The guy from where Christie lived? - No.
失蹤的那個傢伙  也就是曾經被警察逮捕定罪的那個傢伙
The guy who disappeared, the one they made the beef on.
- 你認得那個人嗎  - 是呀
- Know the guy I mean? - Yeah.
他叫貝茲  他手下的人像瘋了一樣到處找他
His name was Batts. His people are driving everyone crazy looking for him.
沒人知道他去哪裏了
Nobody knows what happened to him.
有天晚上他到我店來過  他走之後就失蹤了
He came into the joint that night and then just disappeared. That was it.
好  眼睛放亮一點  他們一直來跟我囉嗦
All right. Keep your eyes open. They're busting my balls over it.
- 好嗎  - 我會的
- All right? - Yeah.
好吧  大家來吃吧
Okay, everybody, let's eat.
我要我的錢
I want my money.
他欠我
He owes it.
還記得郊外那件事嗎
You know that thing we took care of upstate?
- 保利剛才還提到呢  - 我們得把他挖出來
- Paulie was talking about that. - Got to get it out of there.
那塊地就要開始建大廈了
They just sold the property to make condominiums.
- 已經六個月了呀  - 我們要馬上把他移走
- It's been six months. - We got to get it out of there right away.
亨利  快點好不好  我媽要給我們炸香腸吃
Henry, hurry up. My mother's making fried peppers and sausage for us.
- 這有隻手臂  - 很好笑呀
- Here's an arm. - Very funny, guys.
這兒有條腿
Here's a leg.
這兒有只翅膀
Here's a wing.
你喜歡什麼  大腿還是翅膀  心還是肺
What do you like, the leg or the wing? Or you still go for the hearts and lungs?
真臭死了
Oh, that's so bad.
車子怎麼了
What happened to the car?
我撞死了一隻臭鼬
I hit a skunk, all right?
跟媽媽走吧
Go with your mother.
真是噁心死了  亨利
It's disgusting, Henry.
我把珍麗絲安頓在離家不遠的公寓裏
I set up Janice in an apartment around the corner from The Suite.
那樣我每星期可以在她那兒過夜一兩次
That way I was able to stay over a couple of nights a week.
這是新買的古董檯燈
This is my new antique lamp.
凱倫從來不過問我的事  她只在家裏帶孩子
Karen was home with the kids. She never asked questions.
傢俱都是設計家摩瑞斯的作品
The furniture's all Maurice Valencia.
好像是羅馬的作品
Looks like Roma.
這些都是真絲的  從暹羅進口的
This is all silk. This is from Siam.
來看我的臥房
Come see my bedroom.
- 湯米  你抱他一下好嗎  - 我今晚就把他吃掉
- Tommy, will you take him? - I'll eat this fucking dog tonight.
喜歡那個水晶球嗎
Love that crystal ball or what?
我們多數時間都是在這裏消磨的
This is where we spend most of our time.
那盆花插得真美
I love the floral arrangements.
法國貨呀
French.
珍麗絲只顧和我一起玩樂  工作上出軌了
Janice and I were having so much fun, she started screwing up at work.
我只好去給她老闆一點教訓
I had to straighten out her boss a little bit.
珍麗絲喜歡怎麼做  她就可以怎麼做  你懂嗎
Janice can do what she wants to do. Got it?
隨便你往哪裏跑  如果你再掛我的電話  你試試看
Just try to run. Hang up once more, and you'll deal with me.
好了啦  放開她
Come on, get off of her.
你真是個野獸
You're an animal.
小蜘蛛  過來帶杯酒給我
Spider, on your way over here, bring me a Cutty and water.
- 你們吃飯了沒有  - 我餓死了
- Did you guys eat? - I'm starving.
- 打就打啦  - 那些你也能打
- I'll play these. - You'll play those?
我有口吃嗎  那些我都打
Do I stutter? I play those.
我是什麼  我不存在呀
What am I? A mirage?
什麼  我的酒呢
Where's my fucking drink? I asked you for a drink.
- 你有說要酒嗎  - 我剛才跟你說要酒呀
- You wanted a drink? - I asked you for one.
我以為你是說  我不用了  小蜘蛛
I thought you said, "I'm all right, Spider."
你把我例入不用理會的名單嗎
Am I on a pay-no-mind list?
不是的  我聽到有人叫  小蜘蛛  小蜘蛛
No, I heard someone say "Spider, Spider."
- 我以為是亨利在叫吧  - 你簡直是又笨又口吃的蠢貨
- I thought it was Henry. - You're a mumbling, stuttering little fuck.
我以為你說  我不用了  小蜘蛛
I thought you said, "I'm all right, Spider."
你麻煩大了
You ain't all right.
我真的以為你說  沒事了
No, I thought you said you were all right.
我是沒事  你就有事了
I am all right! You ain't, you prick.
你說了一晚上了  小王八蛋
You've been doing this all fucking night to me, you motherfucker!
你現在要不要酒  我去給你拿
He wants a drink now? I'll bring it.
去給我倒酒  快點呀  你個小混球
Go get me a fucking drink! Move it, you little prick.
你走路好像史帝芬·費區一樣慢
You walk like fucking Stepin Fetchit.
為我跑快點行不行
For everybody else you run.
一面跳舞一面抱酒拿過來!
Run for me, you prick! Dance, dance the fucking drink back here!
像鮑嘉在什麼電影裏一樣
What's that movie that Bogart made?
- 就是他扮牛仔那部  - 奧克拉荷馬小子
- Where he played a cowboy. - The Oklahoma Kid.
- 奧克拉荷馬小子  史恩  - 我就是奧克拉荷馬小子
- Shane? - Oklahoma Kid, that's me!
你這沒用的東西  跳舞呀
You fucking varmint. Dance!
你這混蛋
Yahoo, you motherfucker!
把小孩和婦女藏妥
Round up those fucking wagons.
現在他動作可快了
Now he's moving.
- 亨利  怎麼樣了  - 你打中他的腳了  湯米
- Henry, what happened? - He shot him in the foot, Tommy.
他沒事啦  腳被射中了又怎樣  算是件大事嗎  是不是
He's fucking fine. So he got shot in the foot. What is it? A big fucking deal?
- 維多  拿條毛巾來  - 玩得好
- Get a towel. - Nice fucking game.
帶他去看寶凱西醫生吧
Take him to Ben Casey, the little prick.
讓他爬去  就像他拿酒的時候一樣慢慢爬
Let him crawl like he crawls for the drinks.
帶他去看街口那個醫生
Take him to the doctor down the street.
我的腳骨頭全碎了
Bones are all shattered.
不要再惹我生氣了
Don't get me upset, now.
沒什麼大不了的  小蜘蛛  你這小混球
Don't make a big fucking thing out of it, Spider, you little prick.
你們想要我為這件事抱歉嗎
You trying to make me think what the fuck I did here.
那只是件意外而已
It was an accident.
- 別演戲了  小子  - 我這手牌很不錯
- Little fucking actor. - I got a great hand here.
- 這一手你跟不跟呀  - 跟了
- You in or out? - Yeah, I'm in.
- 800元  - 800元
- $800. - $800?
你已經兩星期沒回家了  今天晚上不准出去!
You haven't been home in two weeks. You're not going out tonight!
凱倫  別孩子氣好不好  我還是要出去的
Karen, will you grow up! Stop! I'm still gonna go out!
車鑰匙不給你  你去呀
Not without your car keys, you're not.
你瘋啦  是不是
Are you nuts? What's your problem?
是  我是瘋了  你在玩什麼花樣
Yes, I'm nuts. Something's going on.
- 別說了  夠了  不要說了  - 不好
- Stop with that. Enough! Stop with that. - No!
我告訴你  我看你的臉  就知道你在說謊
I'm telling you, I look in your face and I know that you're lying!
- 滾出去  - 閉嘴
- Get out! Get out! - Shut up.
滾出我的生活
Get out of my life!
你昏頭了  一切都是你想像出來的
You're fucked in the head, Karen. This is all in your mind.
- 你是個低級的混蛋  - 你腦子有問題
- You're a lousy bastard! - You got a problem.
去呀  去找你的現成妓女呀  你只配找那種女人
Go ahead, go to your ready-made whores. That's all you're good for!
滾出我的生活  我不能忍受你了
Get out of my life! I can't stand you!
小蜘蛛  急什麼嘛
Spider, what's your rush?
- 給你  - 謝謝你  小蜘蛛
- Here you go. - Thank you, Spider.
小蜘蛛  你腳上的紗布包得比你的頭還大
Spider, that fucking bandage on your foot is bigger than your fucking head.
下一次他就要用手杖來走路了
Next thing you know, he's gonna be coming in one of these fucking walkers.
雖然你腳受傷了  你還是可以跳舞吧
Even though you got that, you can dance?
給我們表演幾步  你這個裝模作樣的混球
Give us a couple of fucking steps, Spider. You fucking bullshitter, you.
說實話吧  你是希望大家同情你
Tell the truth. You're looking for sympathy?
你去操你自己吧  湯米
Why don't you go fuck yourself, Tommy?
我不相信我所聽到的
I didn't fucking hear right. Can't believe what I heard.
小蜘蛛  這個給你  有種
Spider, here. This is for you. Attaboy.
我看得起這小子  有勇氣
I got respect for this kid. He's got a lot of fucking balls.
不吃任何人這一套
Good for you. Don't take no shit off nobody.
他打中他的腳  他叫他去操自己
He shoots him in the foot, he tells him to go fuck himself.
你就讓這小混球這樣罵你
Are you gonna let this fucking punk get away with that?
你怎麼回事呀  這成什麼世界啦
What's the matter? What's the world coming to?
就成這樣的世界  你認為如何
That's what the fucking world is coming to. How do you like that?
- 行了吧  - 你發瘋啦你
- How's that, all right? - What's the fucking matter with you?
你是笨蛋還是什麼
What are you, stupid or what?
湯米  我是在跟你開玩笑  你是神經不正常了是不是
Tommy, I'm kidding with you. Are you a fucking sick maniac?
我怎麼知道你是開玩笑  你是在糗我
How do I know if you're kidding? You're breaking my fucking balls?
我在開你的玩笑  你卻開槍
I'm fucking kidding with you, you fucking shoot the guy?
他死了
He's dead.
射得真準  你要我怎麼辦嘛  我就是准
Good shot. I'm a lucky man. Good shot.
這種距離會射不準嗎
You can't miss at this distance.
怎麼  你有什麼意見嗎
You got a problem with what I did, Anthony?
沒有
No.
反正是個爛人  他全家都是告密者
Fucking rat. His whole family's all rats. He would've grown up to be a rat.
真是蠢到極點了  我真不敢相信你會做這種事
Stupid bastard! I can't fucking believe you.
你自己去挖坑吧  我沒法處理
Now you're going to dig the hole. I got no fucking lime.
誰在乎  我自己會挖坑  這又不是我第一次挖坑
I'll dig the hole. I don't give a fuck. Is it the first hole I dug?
我去挖就是了  鏟子在哪
I'll dig the fucking hole. Where are the shovels?
- 哈羅  - 哈羅
- Hello. - Hello?
這是凱倫·希爾  我要跟你談談
This is Karen Hill. I wanna talk to you.
哈羅  不要掛上
Hello? Don't hang up on me!
我要和你說話
I want to talk to you!
你離我丈夫遠一點  聽見沒有
You keep away from my husband, you hear me?
哈羅  把門打開
Hello? Open the door!
回答我
Answer me!
我要告訴每一個走進大樓的人
I'm gonna tell everyone who walks in this building...
住在2R的羅茜是妓女
that in 2R, Rossi, you are nothing but a whore!
是不是管理員
Is this the superintendent?
我是要告訴你  有個妓女
Yes, I want you to know, sir, that you have a whore...
住在你大廈的2R房間
living in 2R!
羅茜  珍麗絲·羅茜  你聽見了嗎
Rossi, Janice Rossi. Do you hear me?
他是我丈夫
He's my husband!
有本事自己找個男人
Get your own goddamn man!
醒醒  亨利
Wake up, Henry.
- 凱倫  你瘋啦  - 我是瘋了
- Karen, are you crazy? - I am crazy.
瘋得足以殺掉你們
I'm crazy enough to kill both of you.
凱倫  別動氣好不好
Karen, take it easy.
- 好不好  - 你愛不愛她
- Okay? - Do you love her?
愛不愛
Do you?
- 愛不愛  - 凱倫
- Do you? - Karen...
我愛你  你知道我愛你的
I love you. You know I love you.
你不愛我
You don't.
不  你不愛我
No, you don't.
當心點  凱倫  求求你
Please, be careful. Baby, don't.
我還是沒辦法傷害他
But still I couldn't hurt him. How could I hurt him?
我連離開他的勇氣都沒有
I couldn't even bring myself to leave him.
說實在的
The truth was...
不管我再怎麼生氣
that no matter how bad I felt...
他對我還是有吸引力
I was still very attracted to him.
我為什麼要拱手把他讓給她呢
Why should I give him to someone else?
誰說要她贏我輸
Why should she win?
把槍放下來
Just put it down.
你知道我是愛你的  不是嗎
You know I love you, don't you?
我全心全意只要你
You're all I want, Karen.
凱倫  請把槍放下來
Please put the gun down, Karen.
拜託啦  寶貝
Baby, come on.
你是瘋了是不是  凱倫
What are you, fucking crazy, Karen?
外面的事就夠叫我提心吊膽的了
I got enough to worry about getting whacked on the street!
我回來還要面對這個
I got to fucking come home for this?
我真該殺了你
I should fucking kill you!
這是什麼滋味
How does it feel?
這是什麼滋味  凱倫
How does it feel, Karen?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry!
吉米  你好嗎
Hi, Jimmy! How are you?
- 看來挺好嘛  - 謝謝  很高興見到你
- Looking good. - Thank you. Good to see you.
- 保利  - 甜心  你好吧
- Hi, Paulie! - Hi, honey. How are you?
很好呀
Good.
- 你去幫我買包香煙好嗎  - 好
- Why don't you go get cigarettes, okay? - Sure.
- 你們需要什麼嗎  - 不用
- Any of you need anything? - I'm all right.
- 你們要喝什麼嗎  啤酒  - 不用
- Want anything to drink? A beer? - No.
- 來點中國菜  - 不用  過來坐下
- Chinese food? - No, come on, sit down.
凱倫來看我了
Karen came to the house.
她很氣憤
She's very upset.
這樣很不好  你要把你們的問題解決一下
This is no good. You gotta straighten this thing out.
我們一定要冷靜  她什麼事都做得出來
We got to have calm now. We don't know what the hell she's gonna do.
她已經歇斯底里了  很容易興奮
She's getting all hysterical. She gets very excited.
她很激動  你就得慢慢來  別忘了還有孩子
She's wild. And you got to take it easy. You got children.
我不是說要你馬上回去  不過你還是非回去不可
I'm not saying you gotta back to her this minute, but you gotta go back.
你別無選擇  你得注意自己的形象
It's the only way. You gotta keep up appearances.
凱倫跟美琪每天到我家來訴苦
The two of them come over every day, commiserating.
我受不了了
I can't have it.
亨利  我不能那樣
I can't do it, Henry.
沒人說你不能做你喜歡的
Nobody says that you can't do what you wanna do.
我們知道是怎麼回事
We all know that. I mean, this is what it is.
可是你要面面俱到
We know what it is. You have to do the right thing.
你不能不顧到你的家庭  懂嗎
You have to go home to the family, you understand?
你就是得回家  知道嗎
You got to go home, okay? Look at me.
你就是得回家  放聰明一點
You gotta go home. Smarten up.
- 好嗎  - 好吧
- All right? - All right.
我會跟凱倫講講
I'm gonna talk to Karen.
我會把事擺平  我知道該對她說些什麼
I'll straighten this out. I know just what to say to her.
我會說你願意回去
I'm gonna tell her you'll go back to her...
一切跟以前一樣
and it'll be just the way it was when you were first married...
我會說得很動人  會很圓滿的
your romance, it's gonna be beautiful.
跟她談  我很有把握
I know how to talk to her, especially to her.
吉米跟湯米要到天波城
Jimmy and Tommy are going down to Tampa this weekend...
去幫我拿東西
to pick up something for me.
你代替湯米和吉米去好了
Instead, you go with Jimmy.
你來和我一起去吧
You come with me, we'll go down.
好好玩玩  讓自己輕鬆一下
Have a good time. Take some time for yourself. Relax.
在太陽底下好好休息
Sit in the sun. Take a couple days off.
- 我們會玩得很愉快的  - 好好玩
- We'll have a good time. - Enjoy yourselves.
但當你回來時  你就要回到凱倫身邊
And when you come back, you go back to Karen.
拜託你了  別無他法
Please, there's no other way.
你不能離婚  我們不是禽獸
You're not gonna get a divorce. We're not animali.
他們不會離婚  她永遠不會同意離婚
No divorce. She'll never divorce him.
她會殺了他  但不會跟他離婚
She'll kill him, but she won't divorce him.
你到底付不付
You gonna pay us?
佛羅里達州天波市  兩天後
- 你付錢呀  - 快把錢給我們
- You gonna pay? - Give us the fucking money!
我沒有  我真的沒有
I can't, I swear.
我們走
Let's go.
天波市立動物園
- 我們把這個雜種丟給獅子  - 不要呀
- We'll throw the bastard to the lions. - No!
什麼獅子  我可不要進去  吉米
What fucking lions? I ain't going near any lions, Jimmy!
- 把他丟過分界溝就行了  - 那好
- Let's throw him over the moat. - All right.
我一定把錢給你們
I'll get the money!
一定要有人被喂獅子
They must really feed each other to the lions down there...
那傢伙馬上就付錢了
because the guy gave the money right up.
我對上帝發誓我會付錢
I swear to Christ, I'll get the money.
我們在賽馬場度週末
We got to spend the rest of the weekend at the track.
他們不是開玩笑的
Yeah. They mean business.
接著發生的真的難以相信
Then, I couldn't believe what happened.
當我們回到家的時候  我們已經是新聞人物了
When we got home, we were all over the newspaper.
最初  我根本不知道那邊會跟媒體有牽連
At first, I didn't even know why we got picked up.
後來才知道被我們揍的人的姐姐
Then I found out that the guy we roughed up...
是FBI打字員
turned out to have a sister working as a typist for the FBI.
誰會想到天下有那麼巧的事
Who could believe it? Of all the fucking people.
她把吉米  我  甚至她弟弟全都抖出來了
She gave up everybody: Jimmy, me, even her brother.
陪審團花了六小時  裁決我們有罪
It took the jury six hours to bring us in guilty.
法官判我和吉米每人十年  好像在發糖果一樣
The judge gave Jimmy and me 10 years like he was giving away candy.
判處你們在國立監獄服刑十年
...ten years in a federal penitentiary.
現在交給檢察官
You will now be turned over to the U.S. Attorney General's office.
來敬你一杯
Toast, guys.
一路平安  祝福你們早日出來
Good trip, good life, get out soon.
一切順利
Good trip, sweetheart.
我們會替你照顧家的
We'll watch the home front.
替我問候那些口交的警衛
Say hello to those blow-job hacks.
別忘了一有機會就佔他們的便宜
Yeah, motherfuck them every chance you get.
有機會我會打電話給你
I'll call you when I get a chance.
送我去監獄吧
Now take me to jail.
在監獄裏  晚餐很重要
In prison, dinner was always a big thing.
先來一道意大利面  接著或魚或肉
We had a pasta course, and then we had a meat or a fish.
保利因藐視法庭被判了一年  他負責準備工作
Paulie did the prep work. He was doing a year for contempt...
他有一套切大蒜的訣竅
and had this wonderful system for doing the garlic.
用刀片切得很薄
He used a razor, and he used to slice it so thin...
放在鍋裏  加上一點油就化了
that it used to liquefy in the pan with just a little oil.
那方法很好
It was a very good system.
韋力掌管蕃茄汁
Vinnie was in charge of the tomato sauce.
聞到了沒有
Get the smell?
這肉丸裏有三種肉
Three kinds of meat in the meatballs:
有小牛肉  牛肉和豬肉
Veal, beef, and pork.
那好  反正豬肉是一定要的
Good, but you gotta have the pork.
那是主要的味道來源
That's the flavor.
我覺得他洋蔥放多了  但味道還是很好
I felt he used too many onions, but it was still a very good sauce.
韋力  不要放太多洋蔥
Vinnie, don't put too many onions in the sauce.
我沒放太多
I didn't put too much onions in, Paul.
只放了三個小的而已
Put three small onions, that's all I did.
三個洋蔥  那你放了幾罐蕃茄醬
Three onions? How many cans of tomatoes you put in there?
- 兩大罐  - 你不需要放三個洋蔥
- I put two big cans. - You don't need three onions.
強尼煎牛排
Johnny Dio did the meat.
因為沒有烤箱  強尼用平底鍋做菜
We had no broiler, so Johnny did everything in pans.
他每次都把屋子裏弄得烏煙瘴氣
It used to smell up the joint something awful...
警衛都被熏死了  但他的牛排還真是不錯
and the hacks used to die, but he still cooked a great steak.
- 你的牛排要怎麼樣  - 半生的
- How do you like yours? - Medium rare.
半生  貴族一個
Medium rare. An aristocrat.
當你想到監獄  腦中就會出現像電影中那樣
You know, when you think of prison you get pictures in your mind...
一排排的人被關在鐵欄杆後面
of all those old movies with rows of guys behind bars.
對兄弟來說不是那樣的
It wasn't like that for wiseguys.
並不是那麼槽  除了我很想念吉米
It really wasn't that bad, excepting that I missed Jimmy...
他在亞特蘭大受刑
who was doing his time in Atlanta.
順便給我兩塊牛排  好不好
Give me two steaks while you're in there, all right?
在裏面的人都是嚴格地在受刑  混在一起像豬一樣
Everyone else in the joint was doing real time, mixed together, living like pigs.
可是我們單獨生活  一切都由我們控制
But we lived alone. We owned the joint.
用球棒把那兩個狗娘養的臉打爛了  認都認不出來
We batted them sons of bitches. You couldn't recognize them.
太好了  活該
Good, they deserved it.
雖然有些警衛不受賄  但他們也不會告發我們
Even the hacks we couldn't bribe would never rat on the guys we did.
這樣才對  朋友鄰居間應該互相尊重
...had respect. People loved one another.
夜不閉戶
They left their doors open.
抱歉  久等了
Sorry it took so long.
那個瘦子警衛越來越令人討厭了
The skinny guard's getting to be a real pain in the ass.
- 是該給那個雜種一點教訓了  - 我已經擺平了
- We're gonna have to do something. - I took care of him.
你帶了些什麼來
What'd you bring?
- 麵包  - 好
- Bread. - Good.
- 才烤出來的  - 韋力  你的辣椒和洋蔥有了
- Fresh. - Vinnie, I got your peppers and onions.
香腸  火腿  還有很多奶酪
Salami, prosciutto, a lot of cheese.
還有呢  還有什麼別的
Come on, what else?
- 威士忌  - 好
- Scotch. - Nice.
- 紅酒  - 好了
- Some red wine. - Okay.
- 我們可以吃了  - 我也拿了白葡萄酒
- Now we can eat. - I got some white, too.
白葡萄酒也給我  太美了
Give me the white, too. Beautiful.
來吧  夥計們  我們可以吃了  已經好了  韋力
Okay, boys, let's eat. Come on, it's ready, Vinnie.
這裏還有些麵包
Some more bread.
明天我們吃三明治  你該節食了  韋力
Tomorrow we eat sandwiches. You got to go on a diet, Vinnie.
- 你別開玩笑了  - 你最好聽我的
- You must be kidding. - Believe me.
你在忙什麼
What are you doing?
我也來一點
I'll take that.
- 好  晚一點見  - 對
- All right, I'll catch you guys later. - Yeah.
去公園散散步  是不是
You going for a walk in the park?
- 好  下禮拜見  謝謝  - 好
- Okay, I'll catch you next week. Thanks. - Okay.
- 還有沒有  - 沒了  全光了  週末愉快
- Is there any more? - No, that's it. Have a good weekend.
- 謝啦  - 亨利  再見了
- Thanks. - You too, Henry.
來
Come on.
好好站在這兒
You girls stay right here.
- 你們兩個牽著手  - 好了  一直走到前面去
- I want you to hold hands. - Okay, go right up to the front.
- 走吧  - 你好嗎
- Let's go. - How you doing?
- 還行  你呢  - 很好  謝謝你
- Good, how are you? - Very well, thank you.
- 你講什麼呀  - 我在登記簿上看到她的名字了
- What you talking about? - I saw her name in the register.
- 老天呀  - 你要她來看你嗎
- Jesus Christ. - You want her to visit you?
讓她為你哭整晚不睡  還寫信給假釋管理局
Let her stay up all night crying and writing letters to the parole board.
你以為我在這兒做什麼  我在坐牢呀
What am I doing here? Where am I? I'm in jail.
我不能阻止別人來看我呀
I can't stop people from coming to see me.
好呀  讓她每星期替你偷運這些東西進來
Good, let her sneak this stuff in for you every week.
- 讓她每星期來和那些雜種警衛打交道  - 你這是幹什麼
- Let her fight these bastards every week! - Look what you're doing! Stop it!
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
讓她來替你把這些狗屎運進來
Let her sneak this shit in for you.
你夠了沒有  凱倫
Will you stop it, Karen?
- 讓她去做所有的事嘛  - 夠了
- Let her do it! - Stop it!
我好孤獨  沒有人要幫我
Nobody's helping me. I'm all alone.
貝兒和摩裏都破產了
Belle and Morrie are broke.
我向你的朋友利摩討他欠你的錢
I asked your friend Remo for the money that he owes you.
你知道他說什麼嗎
You know what he told me?
他叫我把孩子們帶到警察局去領救濟金
He told me to take my kids down to the police station and get on welfare.
一切會過去的
It's gonna be okay.
就連保利  他出去後我也沒見到他  我都沒見到他們了
Even Paulie, since he got out, I've never seen him. I never see anybody anymore.
只有我們兩個了
It's only you and me. That's what happens when you go away.
我告訴過你  一旦進了牢就孤立了  忘掉所有的人  忘掉保利
I told you that we're on our own. Forget everybody else. Forget Paulie.
他在保釋期間是不會幫任何人做任何事的
As long as he's on parole, he doesn't want anybody doing anything.
- 我受不了了  - 你能夠忍受  聽我說
- I can't do it. - Yes, you can. Listen to me.
你只要不斷把東西帶來
All I need is for you is to keep bringing me the stuff.
這裏有個從匹茲堡來的  他會幫我銷貨
I got a guy in here from Pittsburgh who'll help me move it.
一個月後我們就安定了
In a month we're gonna be fine.
- 我們不需要別人  - 我害怕
- We won't need anybody. - I'm afraid.
我怕萬一保利知道你私下在販毒
I'm afraid if Paulie finds out...
我不是說了嗎  不要擔心保利
Don't worry about him.
他並沒有幫我們呀  他有沒有供應食物給我們
He is not helping us out. Is he putting any food on the table?
我們只有彼此幫助
We've gotta help each other.
我們的行動一定要特別特別小心
We've just gotta be really careful while we do it.
別讓我再聽到她的名字
I don't want to hear a word about her anymore.
永遠不會了
Never.
四年後
爸爸
Daddy!
- 我們好想念你  - 你會待下來嗎
- We missed you. - Are you here to stay?
你看到我們的畫沒有  那張房子和彩虹是我畫的
Did you see our pictures? I did the one with the house and rainbow.
太陽是我畫的
I did the sun.
我的合唱團兩星期後有音樂會  你能來嗎
My chorus concert is in two weeks. Are you coming?
喜歡我們的房子嗎
Do you like the house?
凱倫  收拾行李  我們要搬家了
Karen, get packed. We're moving out of here.
怎麼搬
With what?
不用擔心  去找新房子就好了
Don't worry, with what. Just start looking for a new house.
明早我要去匹茲堡  那邊有幾個人欠我一萬五千元
I got to go to Pittsburgh in the morning. Those guys there owe me $15,000.
我們沒事了  我都安排好了
We'll be all right. I got things lined up.
匹茲堡  你明天要去向你的假釋官報到呀
Pittsburgh? You have to go see your parole officer tomorrow.
凱倫  不要操心了  一切都會沒問題的
Don't worry about it. Everything's gonna be fine.
- 誰要去保利伯伯家  - 我
- Who wants to go to Uncle Paulie's? - Me!
你要什麼
What do you want?
甜心  讓媽媽好好吃飯
Sweetheart, let Mommy eat.
氣色不錯  牢裏有吃得這麼好嗎
You look good. Did you eat this good in the joint?
不要再搞那些勾當了
I don't want any more of that shit.
什麼勾當
What shit?
- 離那些垃圾遠一點  - 保利
- Just stay away from the garbage. - Look, Paulie...
你在裏面做了我不管  你是身不由己
I'm not talking about what you did inside. You did what you had to do.
我指現在  從現在  從這裏開始
I'm talking about now. From now. Here and now.
- 我怎麼會搞那些  - 不要把我當傻瓜
- Why would I get into that? - Don't make a jerk out of me.
千萬不要
Just don't do it.
現在  我要跟你談吉米  你要注意他
I want to talk to you about Jimmy. You gotta watch out for him.
他很能賺錢  但他太狂了  太冒險了
He's a good earner, but he's wild, takes too many chances.
我瞭解吉米  你想我會像他那樣冒險嗎
I know Jimmy. You think I would take chances like him?
湯米也是個好孩子  但他太瘋了
Tommy's a good kid, but he's crazy.
他是個牛仔  他樣樣都想表現
He's a cowboy. He's got too much to prove.
你不能不自己小心
You gotta watch out for kids like this.
我太清楚他們的個性了  我只利用他們做些事
I know what they are. I only use them for certain things.
我不要像蓋比那樣被人糟蹋  你明白嗎
I ain't gonna get fucked like Gribbs, you understand?
蓋比已經70歲了  他將老死獄中  那不是我所要的
Gribbs is 70 years old. The fucking guy's gonna die in prison. I don't need that.
所以我現在警告每一個人  連我兒子在內
So I'm warning everybody. Everybody. Could be my son, could be anybody.
就因為蓋比手下的人
Gribbs got 20 years just for saying hello to some fuck...
在他背後販毒  他被判20年
who was sneaking behind his back, selling junk.
我絕不容許這種事發生在我身上  你懂了嗎
I don't need that. That won't happen to me, understand?
你能提早出來  是因為我給你找了份工作
You know you're out early because I got you a job.
我不要整天被條子監視  明白嗎
I don't need this heat, you understand that?
如果你看到任何人在販毒  你一定要來告訴我
You see anybody fucking around with this shit you're gonna tell me, right?
不管是誰
That means anybody.
對不對
All right.
對  當然
Yeah. Of course.
我花了一個星期明查暗訪  才把那批匹茲堡貨賣掉
Took me about a week of sneaking around before I could unload the Pittsburgh stuff.
不過我著實賺了一大筆
But when I did, it was a real score.
我開始利用珊蒂的家來混合毒品
I started using Sandy's place to mix the stuff.
雖然她吸的比她配的還多
And even with Sandy snorting more than she mixed...
但還是利潤極大的生意
I could see that this was a really good business.
第二個禮拜我就賺了一萬兩千元
I made $12,000 in my second week.
為我的房子付了頭期款  事情越來越順利了
I had a down payment on my house and things were really rolling.
我只要偶爾告訴珊蒂我愛她就好了
All I had to do was every once in a while tell Sandy that I loved her.
這種安排太完美了
But it was perfect, I'm telling you.
只要貨是從匹茲堡來的
As long as I kept getting the stuff from Pittsburgh...
保利絕不可能發覺
I knew Paulie would never find out.
幾個禮拜之後生意做大了  我一個人處理不了
Within a couple of weeks, it got so big I needed some help.
就把吉米和湯米拉了進來
So I got Jimmy and Tommy to come in with me.
真夠棒的
It's fucking great.
康威先生
Mr. Conway.
- 你薪水單帶來沒有  - 有
- Bring your pay slips? - Yeah.
保釋部
興建工程花了四個半月
Four and a half months of dirt.
- 真好呀  - 撐過來了
- It's so good. - I did it.
- 你喜歡嗎  - 真是太棒了
- Do you love it? - It's wonderful.
這個訂做的  你坐坐看  貝兒
And this we just had to have made special. Go ahead, sit in it, Belle.
有的坐下去真不舒服
The others you couldn't even sit in.
好了  準備好
Okay, you ready?
看著石壁
Watch the wall with the rock.
電工特別設計的
The electricians did it special. Come on.
來呀  來這邊
Come on. All right.
這是進口貨  兩件組合起來的
This was imported. It came in two pieces. Do you believe what they can do?
不錯
It's nice, huh?
亨利  到這邊來  你跟吉米商量過了沒有
Henry, come over here. Did you and Jimmy talk?
我跟他說過了  他會仔細研究這件事的
I talked to him, and he's looking into everything.
這會讓上次法國航空的劫案看起來像兒童故事
This'll make the Air France haul look like goddamn peanuts.
- 小聲點  - 你確定他會下手  對嗎
- Come on. - He's gonna do it, right?
我不是說了嗎  他要好好研究一下
I told you. He'll check everything out.
然後再做決定  沒有任何承諾
He's looking into it. We'll see what happens. No promises.
我知道  你知道嗎  那兒有好幾百萬
I know. Do you understand? There's millions in there. And I've been...
我想對這批貨下手想得都快吐血了  我栽培這個傢伙兩年了
bleeding for this caper, been cultivating this son of a bitch for two years.
這傢伙欠我兩萬塊  一輩子就一次  我可以退休了
He owes me $20,000. Once in a lifetime. I could retire.
不用再為錢操心  我的好夢就要成真了
No more nut every week. No more bullshit. My dream comes true.
來吧  我們來喝一杯吧
Morrie, let's get a drink.
這就是吉米召集在一起
These are the guys that Jimmy put together for what turned out to be...
犯下美國歷史上最大劫案 德航劫案 的一批人
the biggest heist in American history: The Lufthansa heist.
湯米跟卡本負責抓住門口警衛
Tommy and Carbone were gonna grab the outside guard...
逼他開大門
and make him get us in the front door.
法國仔和周佛負責把工作人員集中在一起
Frenchy and Joe Buddha had to round up the workers.
強尼負責把貨綁起來  以免觸到警鈴
Johnny Roastbeef had to keep them all tied up and away from the alarms.
就連史達克也被拉進來了
Even Stacks Edwards got in on it.
他常彈吉他  大家都喜歡他
He used to hang around the lounge and play guitar. Everybody loved Stacks.
他的任務是偷輛大卡車
What he was supposed to do was steal the panel truck...
事後由紐澤西州朋友處理掉
and afterwards compact it by a friend of ours out in Jersey.
只有摩裏真的煩死人了
Only Morrie was driving us nuts.
摩裏  喝一杯酒  然後閉嘴
Morrie, have a drink and shut up.
因為這次的劫案是他從中拉線的
Just because he set this up, he felt he could bust Jimmy's balls...
摩裏就以為他可以向吉米預支是理所當然的事
for an advance on the money we were going to steal.
他並沒有什麼其他的意思  他就是這樣的人
He didn't mean anything by it. That's just the way he was.
我讓每個人都替我做事  就連以前的嬰兒保姆也在內
I had everybody working for me. Even our old baby-sitter, Lois Byrd.
飛機還穩吧
Did you have a good flight?
我恨匹茲堡  你在哪裏找到那些爛人的
I hate Pittsburgh. Where did you find such creeps?
好啦  沒那麼糟啦
Come on, they're not that bad.
跑這一趟是值得的  對嗎
And it's worth it, isn't it?
你上禮拜用的是不是這個嬰兒
Is this the same baby you used last week?
不  上次是我姐姐的嬰兒  這次是狄娜的
No, that one was my sister's. This is Deirdra's.
打哈欠了
Big yawn.
她長得好像你呀
She looks just like you.
空中小姐也這麼說
That's what the stewardess said.
別那麼狠好不好  珊蒂
Take it easy, Sandy.
饒了我吧  我們這裏有的是呀
Come on, give me a break. You got enough here to go around.
少吸一點  你還有一整天  一次太多就不夠用了
You got all day. Just make it last, all right? Take it easy.
- 我得走了  - 你去哪裏
- I got to go. - Where are you going?
不要跟我爭  你知道我要去辦事  操  我的車鑰匙呢
Don't start. You know I gotta go do this thing. Fuck, where are my keys?
就在那裏
Over there.
真夠亂的  像豬窩一樣
It's a mess. It's like a pig pen.
洗碗機買來是做什麼的
What do you think I got you the dishwasher for?
我討厭洗碗  弄壞我指甲
I hate doing the dishes. Fucks up my nails.
我不管你討不討厭洗碗  你要放聰明點
How could you hate it? You got to be smart.
就憑這些白粉  被抓到了我們就別想出來了
Look at all this powder around here. That could put us away forever.
- 別這麼緊張嘛  - 你想幹什麼
- Loosen up. - What are you doing?
- 我得走了  - 你哪兒也不用去
- You know, I gotta... - You don't have to go anywhere.
讓他們等
Make them wait.
今晨黎明前  肯尼迪機場的德國航空貨運站被劫
Nobody knows for sure just how much was taken in the daring pre-dawn raid...
沒人能確定被劫的數目
at the Lufthansa cargo terminal at Kennedy Airport.
FBI說是兩百萬  航空警察說四百萬
The FBI says $2 million, Port Authority Police say $4 million...
吉米
Jimmy!
你們這些狗娘養的
Those sons of bitches!
在肯尼迪機場被劫的現場轉播
...from the scene of the heist at JFK.
看起來也許是本市歷年來最大的一宗劫案
It looks like a big one. Maybe the biggest this town has ever seen.
過來  過來
Come here, you! Come here!
看看這個天才  這是個天才
Look at this genius. This genius!
聖誕快樂
Merry Christmas.
- 哈羅  這是誰呀  - 這是我太太
- Hello, who's this? - That's my wife.
你過來  給你看一樣東西
Come here. I want to show you something, Jimmy.
它美吧
Isn't she gorgeous?
我買給我老婆的  是兩門的  我愛死它了
I bought it for my wife. It's a coupe. I love that car.
我怎麼跟你說的  我確實跟你說過的
What did I tell you? I talked to you before, didn't I?
你不瞭解情況嗎
Didn't I say what was going on?
我沒告訴你暫時不要買東西嗎
Didn't I say not to go buy anything for a while?
- 竟然買輛新車  - 是我媽送的
- The fucking car? - It's a wedding gift from my mother.
車主也是她  我才剛結婚呀
It's under her name. I just got married.
- 我好愛那輛車  - 對不起  你等一下
- I love that car. - Excuse me, darling, for just a second.
- 我剛結婚耶  - 你是不是瘋了
- I just got married. - Are you nuts?
- 你這麼激動幹什麼  - 你是笨豬呀
- What are you getting excited for? - Are you stupid?
外面有成千上萬警察在注意我們
We got a million bulls out there. Everybody's watching us.
你居然弄了輛新車  還說我激動
And you get a fucking car. I'm excited?
那是我用我媽名字登記的  那是結婚禮物嘛
It's under my mother's name. It's a wedding gift.
我不管是登記誰的名字  你是真笨還是假笨呀
I don't give a fuck. Are you stupid?
你沒聽見我說的嗎  什麼都不要買
Didn't you hear what I said? Don't buy anything.
特別是大東西  你沒聽見我這麼說的嗎
Don't get anything. Nothing big. What's the matter with you?
你到底是怎麼搞的
What are you getting excited for?
因為你會連累我們被捕  你白癡啊
Because you're going to get us all fucking pinched. What are you, stupid?
- 你是怎麼搞的  - 對不起
- What's the matter with you? - I apologize.
- 我道歉  - 你是怎麼搞的
- I'm sorry. - What the fuck is the matter with you?
對不起
I'm sorry.
對不起  吉米  在我媽名下
I'm sorry, Jimmy. It's under my mother's name.
說什麼  你在跟我爭辯嗎
What'd you say? You being a fucking wise guy with me?
- 我錯了  我道歉  - 我是怎麼告訴你的
- I'm sorry. I apologize. - What did I tell you?
聽見沒有  什麼也不許買
What did I tell you? You don't buy anything, you hear me?
什麼也不許買
Don't buy anything!
對不起  吉米
I'm sorry, Jimmy.
那個死胖子  他該掛一個笨蛋的牌子
The fat fuck, he ought to wear a sign.
我真不敢相信有這種事  你是變笨了是不是
I can't believe this. Are you stupid or what?
抱歉
Excuse me.
- 你在做什麼  - 脫下來
- What's the matter? - Take it off.
- 你在搞什麼名堂  - 脫下來
- Why? What's the matter? - Take it off!
難道我沒告訴你不要買名貴的東西  不要引人注意嗎
Didn't I tell you not to get anything big and not to attract attention?
兩天之內  一個買凱迪拉克  一個買貂皮大衣
In two days, one guy gets a Caddy and one gets a $20,000 mink.
- 退回去  - 我會退回去
- Bring it fucking back. - I'll bring it back.
不管怎樣  把東西退回去
I don't care what you do. Bring it where you got it before.
- 把它拿出去  - 好  我聽見了  快點走吧
- Get it out of here! - All right. Let's go, honey.
這種酒比性愛還爽
This drink here is better than sex, babe.
我要去找史達克  不要東張西望  否則宰了你
I'm gonna go see Stacks. Don't you look at anybody or I'll fucking kill you.
他醋勁好大  我不能看別人一眼  他會殺了我
He's so jealous. If I even look at anyone else, he'll kill me.
不錯喔
That's great.
我告訴他們不要引人注意
Tell them all to relax. Don't attract attention.
我一直在找你們
I've been looking all over for you.
聖誕快樂
How are you? Merry Christmas.
我需要錢
Listen, I need the money.
- 輕鬆點  摩裏  好嗎  - 吉米  我需要錢呀
- Morrie, relax, okay? It's Christmas. - Jimmy, I need the money.
我是很輕鬆  但我需要錢
I'm relaxing. I need the money.
- 該做的都做了  我要錢  - 今晚不行  摩裏
- I did what I had to do. I need the money. - Not tonight, Morrie.
你聽著  我給你們計劃得好好的  他欠我那份
Listen, I did my caper. He owes me.
大家都在炫耀新東西
Everybody's flashing their stuff.
顯然他們都拿到錢了  我還在穿舊衣裳
Evidently, they got their money. I'm wearing the same shit.
- 今晚不行  - 他們都穿在身上  我一定要跟他談
- Just not tonight. - They're wearing it. I gotta talk to him.
他應該給我50萬
I got $500,000 coming to me.
他一輩子也沒弄到過這麼多錢
The biggest fucking bundle he ever made in his life.
摩裏  我會跟他說  你去喝杯酒
Morrie, I'll go talk to him. Go have a drink, all right?
- 我去找他談  - 我看這是惡毒
- I'll talk to him. - It's poison in my eyes.
- 摩裏寶貝  你沒事吧  - 我沒事
- Morris, baby, are you all right? - No, I'm not.
吉米
Jimmy
聖誕快樂  你的一份  先嘗嘗味道
Christmas. Your share. Just a little taste.
我們做到了
We did it!
- 吉米  - 是
- Jimmy. - Yeah.
- 誰呀  - 是我
- Yeah, who is it? - It's me.
彼特  等一下
Pete? One second.
不要學法蘭基和強尼  不要暴露
Don't do what Frankie and Johnny did. Don't be a moron with the money.
- 明白嗎  - 當然
- Do what's right, you understand? - Yeah.
凱倫  茱迪  露絲  過來!
Karen, Judy, Ruth, come here!
我買了棵最貴的聖誕樹
I got the most expensive tree they had.
- 媽咪  你說哪一件好看  - 我每件都喜歡
- What do you think, Mommy? - I love them all.
我喜歡金色那件
I love the gold outfit.
- 聖誕快樂  - 謝謝你
- Merry Christmas. - Thank you.
- 嗯  - 聖誕快樂
- What? - Merry Christmas.
還有
And?
快樂漠路卡節
Happy Hanukkah.
- 好笑喔  - 買你喜歡的東西
- Very funny. - Go get yourself something nice, okay?
德航劫案價值六百萬  使我們一生不愁吃穿
Lufthansa should have been our ultimate score. The heist of a lifetime.
每個人都得到一份可觀的數目  這樣其實就應該足夠了
$6 million in cash. More than enough to go around.
史達克  開門呀
Yo, Stacks!
你在幹什麼呀
Open up! What's up? What're you doing?
你怎麼搞的  這傢伙還沒準備好
What's with you? He ain't ready. I knew you wouldn't be ready.
- 你沒帶咖啡來嗎  - 我又不是送外賣的
- You didn't bring any coffee? - What do I look like, a fucking caterer?
法蘭基  煮點咖啡吧  起來呀
Frankie will make coffee. Go ahead, Frankie, make coffee.
我以為你會有個女人在
Thought you had one of your bitches in here.
是有一個  到哪去了
Yeah, I did. Where the fuck is she?
總是少不了黃色書刊和女人
Always got these hot books around, or a bitch, or something.
幾點了
What time is it?
- 11點半了  我們應該9點到的  - 馬上就好
- It's 11:30. We had to be there by 9:00. - I'll be ready in a minute.
你老是遲到  連你自己的葬禮也會遲到
You're always fucking late. You'd be late for your own fucking funeral.
有什麼好看的  把咖啡帶走吧
What the fuck you looking at? Make that coffee to go. Let's go.
我是開玩笑啦  操
What the fuck you doing? It's a joke.
你還真要把咖啡帶走  放下來啦
Put the fucking pot down. You gonna take the coffee?
史達克總是瘋瘋癲癲的
Stacks was always crazy.
他沒有照計劃把卡車處理掉  反而吸大麻吸嗨了
Instead of getting rid of the truck as he was supposed to, he got stoned...
跑去女朋友家  當他醒來  警察已經找到了卡車
went to his girlfriend's, and by the time he woke up, the cops had found the truck.
電視上報告說
It was all over the television.
已在車上找到指紋
They even said they came up with prints off the wheel.
不用多久  他們就會找到史達克的
It was just a matter of time before they got to Stacks.
我必須和你談談
I gotta talk to you.
- 來一杯吧  - 來呀  來一杯
- Have a drink. - Have a drink. Come on.
來一杯  好不容易聚在一起喝一杯
Have a drink. What you doing? It's an occasion. Have a drink.
我還是得跟你談談
I still gotta talk to you.
什麼事呀
What?
- 史達克出了什麼事  - 不要擔心
- What happened with Stacks? - Don't worry about that.
- 到處都是FBI的人  - 那又怎樣  他們能找到什麼
- There's feds all over the place. - So what? Where are they gonna go?
- 報上登出來了  - 他很擔心
- It's in the papers. - He's worried.
你在擔心什麼
What are you worried about?
只是電視上  報上都有消息
The television and the newspapers. All the shit's out there.
- 你到底擔心什麼  - 你太多慮了
- What are you worried about? - You worry too much.
一切美好  什麼都不用擔心
Everything is beautiful. There's nothing to worry about.
- 你告訴他了沒有  - 沒有  我還沒告訴他
- Didn't you tell him? - I didn't tell him yet.
- 什麼事呀  - 猜猜看
- What? - Guess what?
他們要正式讓湯米成為黑手黨一員
They're gonna make him.
保利要引薦你嗎
Paulie's going to make you?
湯米
Tommy.
他們把名單打開了  保利得到批准把他正式加入名單
They opened up the books. Paulie got the okay.
你相信嗎  這個意大利雜種
You believe that? This little guinea bastard.
他要上正式名單了  這傢伙要成我們的上司了
He's gonna get made. We're gonna work for this guy one day. He's gonna be a boss.
我真不敢相信
I can't believe it.
我真為你高興  太好了  恭喜你
I'm really happy for you. Great. Congratulations.
我們現在佔上風了
Motherfuckers, we got them now.
吉米  我到處在找你  我能跟你說幾句話嗎
Jimmy, I've been looking all over for you. Can I talk to you a second?
我做的計劃  結果我什麼也沒得到
I mastermind the goddamn thing, I'm left with dick.
要不是我  他們就很辛苦  我要我的錢
They'd be up a creek if not for me. Fuck him! I want my money.
我受夠了  我要我的錢
I want my money! I've had it up to here!
那個專門劫香煙的下流鬼
That cheap cigarette hijacker.
- 去他的  我要我的錢  - 去呀  去跟他講呀
- Fuck him! I want my money! - Good. Go tell him.
你是不是還要嚷嚷
You're gonna keep your mouth shut, or what?
你會拿到錢的
Morrie, you're gonna get your money.
但你不能老是這樣煩人家
You just got to stop busting balls.
好  看著我  聽見了嗎  看著我
All right? Look at me. You hear me? Look at me, okay?
一切不會有問題的
Everything's going to be fine.
亨利
Henry.
好小子  半愛爾蘭  半意大利人是嗎  我拿意大利腔來唱
Sweetheart, half mick, half guinea? I'll sing with an Italian accent.
我頭一次看到吉米那麼緊張
I could see for the first time that Jimmy was a nervous wreck.
他同時朝八個方向去想
His mind was going in eight different directions at once.
你想摩裏有沒有把什麼事都告訴他太太
Think Morrie tells his wife everything?
摩裏啊
Morrie? Him?
那時候我就知道吉米要把摩裏幹掉
That's when I knew Jimmy was going to whack Morrie.
事情就是這樣  一個人在幾分鐘之內就被決定了要被幹掉
That's how it happens. That's how fast it takes for a guy to get whacked.
你知道他就是那種大嘴巴
He's a nut job. He talks to everybody.
你看過他的電視廣告  像隻豬
Acts like a jerk in his commercials. Nobody listens to what he says.
誰拿他的話當一回事  他整天說個不停
Nobody fucking cares what he says, he talks so much.
今天晚上把他帶來
Make sure you bring him here tonight.
- 知道嗎  - 知道
- Okay? - All right.
就這樣開始  抱歉  我有沒有弄到你眼睛
Start like this. Sorry. Did I get you in the eye?
少惹我了好不好
Stop breaking my balls, all right?
我只是在拖時間
I was just stalling for time.
希望在9點以前能說服吉米
I knew I still had till 8:00 or 9:00 to talk Jimmy out of killing Morrie.
到現在為止  吉米還是認為我同意把摩裏幹掉
But meanwhile, as far as Jimmy knew, I was going along with the program.
我把他頭髮拔出來了  我咬了他  他昏迷了
I pulled his hair out of his fucking head. I bit him. He's out cold.
我氣死了  我要殺了他
I'm enraged. I wanted to kill this little fuck.
所以我先走開了  我們正要進去
I walk away. We start to go in the fucking joint.
我不想轉身  吉米對我這樣
I don't want to turn around. Jimmy's going like this to me.
我不想轉身
I don't want to fucking turn around.
我不想轉身  他媽的  他抬頭說
I don't want to turn around. He picks up his fucking head, he says...
我說  不要講
I said, "Don't say it."
敗類
"Jerkoff!"
還能怎樣  我就向他撲過去
What are you going to do? What? I fucking fly at him.
我抓住他  開始捶他頭  臉
I got him and I'm banging his head, banging his fucking face.
拔他頭髮
I'm pulling his hair out of his head.
我把他打得稀巴爛
I beat him to a pulp. To a pulp I beat him.
他躺著  渾身是血  我在喘氣
He's laying there full of fucking blood. I'm out of breath.
今晚就算了  今晚算了
Forget about tonight. Forget about it.
我心裏的負擔減輕了
It was a load off my mind.
那個傢伙
Poor bastard.
還不知道自己有多危險
He never knew how close he'd come to getting killed.
就算我告訴他  他差點沒命  恐怕他也不會相信的
Even if I told him, he would have never believed me.
- 吉米  現在我能跟你談談嗎  - 你這狗娘養的  你真夠煩人
- Jimmy, could I talk to you now? - You're a pisser. A real pisser.
你要現在談嗎  好吧  我們來做個了斷
Want to talk now? Okay, let's talk. Let's get it over with.
從來沒見過像你這麼難纏的人
I've never met a ball buster like you, my whole life.
誰比我還愛你
Who loves you more than I do?
- 我會為你做任何事  - 除了不肯少來煩我
- I'd do anything for you. - Except to stop busting my balls.
- 我們去喝咖啡吧  - 去餐廳還是別的地方
- Let's go have coffee. - Want to go to the diner?
我們去大道上的餐廳
We'll go to the diner on the boulevard.
- 哪一間呢  - 洛克威大道  24小時營業
- Which diner? - Rockaway Boulevard. It's open 24 hours.
- 有沒有丹麥蛋糕  - 他們什麼都有
- They got Danishes? - They got everything.
我要帶幾個回去給貝兒
Let's pick up some Danishes for Belle.
你有沒有聽到我們在波士頓安排籃球賽放水的事
Hear about the points we were shaving up in Boston?
那真是太棒了
It's terrific. Nunzio...
我以為他永遠也不會閉嘴
I thought he'd never shut up.
沒人比他更令人討厭
What a pain in the ass.
- 你要怎麼處理他  - 把他分屍  丟掉  把車也丟掉
- What'll we do with him? - Chop him up and get rid of the car.
然後打電話給我
Call me when you're through.
- 法蘭基  我們來把他大卸八塊吧  - 好吧
- Frank, let's chop him up. - All right.
你要去哪裏  你昏頭啦
Where you going, you dizzy motherfucker, you?
你不是說要把他解了嗎
You said chop him up.
不是在這裏  去查理那兒  在這裏怎麼切
At Charlie's, not here! Where are you gonna chop him here?
你在做什麼  快離開這裏
Come on, what are you doing? Get out of here.
還不如讓他開車
I got a better shot letting him drive.
車引擎是冷的
The car's cold.
熱什麼鬼車  快離開現場
Get the fuck out of here! What, warm it up? Get out of here!
- 是誰  - 是貝爾  開門
- Who is it? - It's Belle. Open up.
是貝爾  讓我進來
It's Belle. Let me in.
摩裏沒有回家  他失蹤了  我知道他一定出事了
Morris didn't come home. He's missing. I know something's happened.
冷靜一點
Calm down.
他失蹤了  我知道出事了
He's missing! I know something happened.
他大概是喝醉了  倒在那裏睡著了
He's probably drunk and fell asleep somewhere.
27年了  他從來沒有在外過夜  而不打電話給我的
In 27 years, he's never been away all night without calling.
肯定出事了  你們一定曉得
I know something's happened. I know you know.
我上樓去換衣服  先送你回家  然後去找他
Let me get changed. I'll take you home, then look for him.
- 我是從家裏來的  我一直打電話  - 他在玩牌吧
- I've been home! I've been on the phone... - He's playing cards.
- 你要我怎麼跟貝爾講  - 誰他媽在乎
- What'll I tell Belle? - Who gives a fuck?
就說他跟野女人私奔了  關你什麼事
Tell her he ran off with some broad. What do you care?
- 你看  - 不要跟他們作對
- Watch this. - Don't fuck with them.
就算坐一點牢  也總算搗了他們的蛋
I do it all the time. I'll bust their balls.
別給他們這個機會來得意了
Don't give them the satisfaction, the fucks.
走吧  我們去兜風
Come on, fuckos. Let's go for a ride.
他們一夜沒睡了
Keep them up all night.
待會兒見
I'll see you later.
吉米想把每一個能把他和劫案牽連在一起的人都除掉
Jimmy was cutting every link between himself and the robbery...
好在跟我一點關係都沒有
but it had nothing to do with me.
我給吉米一些可劫對象的消息  他則給我錢
I gave Jimmy the tip and he gave me some Christmas money.
之後我沒再提大劫案的事
From then on, I kept my mouth shut.
我知道錢在吉米那裏
I knew Jimmy. He had the cash. It was his.
他只拿一點錢孝敬保利而已
He kicked some money upstairs to Paulie, but that was it.
要他把錢分給有功勞的人  那是不可能的事
It made him sick to turn the money over to the guys who stole it.
他寧願把他們殺了  反正關我什麼事
He'd rather whack them. Anyway, what did I care?
我也不想向吉米要求什麼
I wasn't asking for anything.
吉米倒從我的匹茲堡路線收穫不少
And Jimmy was making nice money through my Pittsburgh connections.
大劫案之後幾個月  仍然到處發現死屍
Still, months after the robbery they were finding bodies all over.
當他們在冷凍車庫裏找到卡本的屍體
When they found Carbone in the meat truck...
他已經冷凍得
he was frozen so stiff...
要花兩天才能解凍  才能拿出來解剖
it took them two days to thaw him out for the autopsy.
我從沒見過吉米那麼高興
Still, I never saw Jimmy so happy.
他簡直像個孩子  匹茲堡給我們帶來錢財
He was like a kid. We had money coming in through my Pittsburgh people...
德航劫案的調查也漸漸冷卻下來
and even after a while, the Lufthansa thing began to calm down.
那天早上令吉米高興的原因
What made Jimmy so happy that morning...
是因為湯米要被引薦
was that this was the day that Tommy was being made.
他興奮得好像他自己要被引薦似的
Jimmy was so excited, you'd think he was being made.
他至少打了四次電話到湯米家
He must have made four calls to Tommy's house.
引薦禮完成之後以信號表示
They had a signal set up, so he'd know the minute the ceremony was over.
- 媽  你在哪兒  - 在這裏呀
- Ma, where are you? - Here I am.
- 你回來啦  - 回來  我正要出去呀
- You're home. - Home? I'm leaving.
- 不錯吧  - 你看起來帥極了
- You look lovely. - I look good, huh?
千萬小心  恭喜你了  祝你好運
You look wonderful. Be careful. Congratulations.
我愛你  別再畫宗教畫了  拜託你
I love you. Don't paint any more religious pictures, please.
- 上帝與你同在  - 再見  媽媽
- God be with you. - Bye, Ma.
我們都以好兄弟互相稱呼
We always called each other goodfellas.
你對某人說
You'd say to somebody:
你會喜歡他  他是好兄弟  是我們一夥的
"You'll like this guy. He's all right. He's a goodfella, one of us."
你明白嗎
You understand?
我們都是好兄弟
We were goodfellas. Wiseguys.
吉米和我都因為有愛爾蘭血統  而不能被引薦
But Jimmy and I could never be made because we had Irish blood.
即便我母親是西西里人也沒有用
It didn't matter my mother was Sicilian.
你一定要百分之百意大利血統才能被正式引薦
To become a member of a crew, you've got to be 100% Italian...
他們要能追蹤出你所有親戚的來歷
so they can trace your relatives back to the old country.
那是最高的榮譽
It's the highest honor they can give you.
象徵你已屬於一個家庭  一個團體
It means you belong to a family and a crew.
那意謂著再沒有人敢傷害你
It means nobody can fuck around with you.
你卻可以任意欺侮
It also means you could fuck around with anybody...
那些不屬於任何家族的人
just as long as they aren't also a member.
好像擁有偷劫的執照  做任何事的執照
It's like a license to steal. A license to do anything.
你被正式引薦有多少年了
How many years ago since you were made?
- 我是老人了  30年前  - 30年前呀
- I'm an old-timer. 30 years ago. - Thirty years?
是呀  有很多值得回憶的事呀
Brings back a lot of memories.
派克山當時也只不過一粒青春痘嘛
Pike's Peak was a pimple then, wasn't it?
對吉米來說  湯米被引薦
As far as Jimmy was concerned, with Tommy being made...
就像我們都被引薦了一樣
it was like we were all being made.
我們之中有人當了會員了
We would now have one of our own as a member.
- 是誰  - 是韋力
- Who's this? - This is Vinnie.
怎麼回事  儀式完成了嗎
Vinnie. What happened? Did we get straightened out?
發生一點問題  我們盡力了
No, we had a problem. We tried to do everything we could.
你是什麼意思
What do you mean?
我是說他死了  我們也無能為力
You know what I mean. He's gone, and we couldn't do nothing about it.
- 就這樣  - 你是什麼意思
- That's it. - What do you mean?
他死了
He's gone.
就這樣
That's it.
我早就知道會這樣  狗娘養的  我不能相信
I knew it! I can't fucking believe it.
發生什麼事啦
What happened?
- 他們幹掉他了  - 操
- They fucking whacked him - Fuck.
你還好嗎
Are you all right?
那是替比利·貝茲報仇
It was revenge for Billy Batts...
還有一些舊的積怨
and a lot of other things.
就是這樣
And that's that.
我們是一點辦法也沒有
There was nothing we could do about it.
貝茲是黑手黨的  湯米還不是
Batts was a made man and Tommy wasn't.
我們只是老老實實的逆來順受
We had to sit still and take it.
意大利人圈子就是這樣  一種毫無道理的規定
It was among the Italians. It was real greaseball shit.
他們甚至打在湯米臉上
They even shot Tommy in the face...
讓他媽媽不能給他開棺瞻仰
so his mother couldn't give him an open coffin at the funeral.
1980年5月11日  星期日  上午6點55分
我本來預備好要忙一整天的
I was gonna be busy all day. I had to drop off some guns at Jimmy's...
我要拿槍去給吉米配消音器
to match some silencers he had.
去醫院接我弟弟  帶他回家吃晚飯
I had to pick up my brother at the hospital and drive him home.
然後去取匹茲堡來的貨
I had to pick up some new Pittsburgh stuff for Lois...
交給露易絲  讓她將貨空運給亞特蘭大附近的客人
to fly down to some customers I had near Atlanta.
我馬上就知道他不會要那些槍  我知道我的錢泡湯了
Right away, I knew he didn't want them, and I'd be stuck for the money.
因為他要我才買的  現在他又不要了
I only bought them because he wanted them, and now he didn't.
這些有什麼鬼用  一個都配不上  你在搞什麼
What good are these? None of them fit. What's the matter with you?
我才不付錢呢
I'm not paying for it.
我一句話也沒講  吉米氣得連再見都沒說
I didn't say a thing. Jimmy was so pissed off, he didn't even say goodbye.
別再吸毒了  你的腦子都快不管用了
Stop the drugs. They're making your mind into mush!
- 聽見沒有  - 我把它們帶回去就是了
- You hear me? - I'll take them back.
上午8點05分
那些匹茲堡傢伙  總是在買槍
My Pittsburgh guys always wanted guns.
我下午反正要去見他們  去取貨
Since I would see them in the afternoon to pick up a delivery...
我蠻肯定我能賺回本的
I was pretty sure I'd get my money back.
我的老天呀
Oh, my God.
上午8點45分
當我終於到了醫院接麥可  醫生說我該住院了
When I finally got to the hospital, Michael's doctor wanted to put me in bed.
上帝呀  你發生什麼事了
Jesus Christ, what happened to you?
剛才差點撞車
I almost got into an accident on the way here.
我描述了車禍  又說昨夜狂歡沒睡
And I told him I was partying all night.
- 我沒事  - 好啦  到這邊來
- I'm fine. - Come on. Get over here.
- 醫師  我沒事  - 我給你做個檢查
- Doc, I'm fine. - Let me check you out.
好啦
Come on.
他很同情我  只給了我10毫克鎮靜劑
He took mercy on me, gave me 10 milligrams of Valium...
就讓我回去了
and sent me home.
我計劃把弟弟送回家  同時把凱倫接上
My plan was to drop off my brother at the house and pick up Karen.
你看見沒有  一架直升機
There it is. You see that helicopter right there?
就在我們前面  它跟了我一早上了
Right in front of us, there. I think it's been following me all morning.
- 別瞎扯了  它跟蹤你幹什麼  - 我告訴你
- Get the fuck out. What are you, nuts? - I'm telling you.
我也不知道是怎麼回事
I don't know what's going on.
這是我第三次看到它  我去醫院接你也看到了
It's the third time I've seen it. At the hospital I saw it.
中途停了兩次  每次都看到它
I had to make some stops. I've seen it every time.
我跑了好多地方  整天都看到它
I've been all over town and I've seen it all day.
那天由我做晚餐
I was cooking dinner that night.
上午11點30分
我必須把肉汁熬出來做蕃茄配料
I had to start braising the beef and veal shanks for the tomato sauce.
是麥可最喜歡的菜  我做了肉醬
It was Michael's favorite. I was making ziti with meat gravy...
還打算烤辣椒
and I'm planning to roast some peppers over the flames...
橄欖油豆  大蒜等
put on some string beans with olive oil. I had some beautiful cutlets...
我還有切得很好的小牛肉
that were cut just right...
打算炸好了當開胃菜
that I was going to fry up as an appetizer.
我在家停留了約一小時
So, I was home for about an hour.
現在我計劃提早吃晚飯
My plan was to start the dinner early...
凱倫和我可以把槍推銷掉
so Karen and I could unload the guns Jimmy didn't want...
同時把貨取回來給露易絲
then get the package for Lois...
由她跑一趟亞特蘭大
to take to Atlanta for her trip later that night.
我不時從窗戶看出去  直升機已經不在了
I kept looking out the window, and I saw that the helicopter was gone.
麥可  注意蕃茄汁好嗎  你留在這裏陪麥可叔叔
Michael, keep an eye on the sauce. Stay here with your Uncle Michael.
我請麥可注意配料  我和凱倫就出去了
So I asked my brother to watch the sauce, and Karen and I started out.
天呀  我看見了
Oh, God. I see it.
- 我看見了  就在那兒  - 該死
- I see it. Look, it's right there. - Damn!
- 就是它  - 就在那邊
- That's it. - There it is.
我們去你媽媽家
We got to get to your mother's.
看見了吧  我告訴你了嘛
See, I told you.
是很奇怪
It's funny.
- 但並不是世界末日  - 我們先去你媽媽家
- It's not the end of the world. - We're going to your mother's.
進去告訴你媽媽  外面的東西不要碰  好嗎
Go inside, tell your mother not to touch anything outside the house. Nothing.
為什麼不到你媽媽家去  非要到我媽家來
We couldn't go to your mother's house? You had to come here.
來  去購物吧
Let's go shopping.
沒有  我沒瘋  這死東西跟了我一早上
I'm not nuts, it's been following me all morning.
中午12點30分
我跟你講啦
I'm telling you.
好啦  好啦  他說我疑心病太重
Fine. Fine. He thinks I'm paranoid!
我應該把直升機帶到他那  看我是不是疑心病
I should bring him the helicopter, then we'll see how paranoid I am.
我們進去吧
Come on, let's go inside.
下午1點30分
不見了
Yeah, it's gone.
-我聽不見聲音了  -來吧  回你媽媽家
- I don't hear anything. - Let's go back to your mother's.
下午3點30分
- 還可以嗎  - 太好了  太好了
- They all right? - Beautiful. They're great.
我不是說了  你是疑心病嗎  我告訴你  他是多心罷了
Didn't I tell you, you were paranoid? Didn't I tell him?
是呀  我需要吸一口
Yeah. I need a hit.
你要看直升機嗎  來  我給你看直升機
Want to see helicopters? Come on, I'll show you helicopters.
我今天看夠直升機了
I've seen enough helicopters for one day, thank you.
我計劃先回家  把包裹準備給露易絲帶上路
I had to get home and get the package ready for Lois to take on her trip.
我還要去珊蒂家  讓她把奎寧注射進去
Also, I had to get to Sandy's to give the package a whack with quinine.
加上珊蒂一定會囉嗦我沒去陪她
Plus, I knew Sandy would get on my ass.
我還得做菜  還有幫助露易絲啟程
I had the cooking to finish, and I had to get Lois ready for her trip.
- 是珊蒂啦  這是怎樣啊  - 她煩得很啦
- It's Sandy. What is this? - She's a pain in the ass.
- 你什麼時候過來  - 我一小時之內會去
- When are you coming over? - In an hour.
- 你今天在我這兒過夜吧  - 不行  我要照顧我弟弟
- You staying tonight, right? - I can't. I got my brother tonight.
好了  別說了  再見
Come on, stop. We'll talk about it later, okay? Goodbye.
- 哈羅  - 你準備好了沒有
- Hello? - It's me. You ready?
叫麥可注意不要讓配料太濃  要不停攪拌
Tell Michael not to let the sauce stick. Keep stirring it.
- 亨利說不要讓配料太濃  - 我在攪拌
- Henry says don't let the sauce stick. - I'm stirring it.
- 你知道該怎麼做嗎  - 知道  知道
- Listen, you know what to do? - Yeah, yeah.
不要跟我來  知道  知道  這一套  這是很重要的事
Don't "yeah, yeah" me, Lois. This is important.
你到外面去再打電話
Make sure you leave the house when you make the call.
懂不懂  用公用電話  你聽見沒有  不是鬧著玩的
Understand me? Call from an outside line. I mean it.
上帝  你把我當呆子呀  少煩我  我知道該怎麼做
Jesus, you must think I'm dumb. Why are you bugging me? I know what to do.
沒常識  你最好別弄糟事情
You little hick, just make sure you do it.
你就是會讓人不舒服
You can be such a pain.
- 你就照我的意思做  - 知道啦
- Hey! Just do it! - Okay.
真沒法相信  我生命中的每個女人都是這樣的
Un-fucking-believable. All of them. Every fucking girl in my life.
- 他說什麼  - 沒什麼
- What did he say? - Nothing.
她掛上電話以後  你猜她做了什麼
What does she do after she hangs up with me?
雖然她說了一大堆  知道  知道  雖然我一再警告她
After everything I told her? After all her "yeah, yeah"bullshit?
她居然拿起電話就打
She picks up the phone and calls from the house.
假如被裝了竊聽器  那對方什麼都清楚了
If anybody was listening, they'd know everything.
一袋包裹將從我家送出
They'd know a package was leaving my house...
甚至班機號碼及時間
and they'd even have the time and flight number, thanks to her.
As soon as I got home, I started cooking.
我一到家就開始做晚餐
傍晚6點30分
離露易絲起飛時間有幾小時
I had a few hours until Lois' flight.
我告訴弟弟注意爐子
I told my brother to watch the stove.
可憐的小子  一整天都在看蕃茄汁和直升機
All day long the guy's been watching helicopters and tomato sauce.
我得去珊蒂家把貨混好再回來做肉汁
I had to drive over to Sandy's, mix the stuff, then get back to the gravy.
晚上8點30分
你以為可以隨便來  下了床  屁股一拍就走人嗎
Do you think you can come over here, fuck me, and leave?
- 別這樣嘛  - 你還有更好的地方要去嗎
- Come on. - You got someplace better to go?
別這樣講
Don't talk like that. Come on.
- 你沒事吧  - 沒事啦
- You all right? - Yeah, sure.
你相信我嗎
You believe me?
Do you believe me?
你相信我嗎
- 那是最後一批了吧  - 是呀
- That the last one? - Yeah.
你這狗娘養的騙子  我恨你
You lying son of a bitch. I hate you!
晚上10點45分
不要在桌子上餵狗
Please stop feeding the dog from the table...
更不要用盤子餵他  不許這樣
from the plate on top of it. Stop it.
- 我不喂不行  - 沒什麼不行的
- I have to. - You don't have to.
我得回家一趟
I got to go home.
什麼叫你得回家一趟
What do you mean, you got to go home?
我帶著這些貨跑了一早上
I've been carrying this all day.
你該開始把它粘在大腿上  我們差不多該走了
We got to start taping it to your leg. We got to go soon.
我要回去拿我的帽子
I got to go home and get my hat.
你在開我玩笑呀  什麼鬼帽子
Forget your fucking hat. Are you kidding me?
要我載你回去拿帽子
So I need a trip to Rockaway because you want your hat?
我需要它  那是我的幸運帽  沒有它我絕不上路
I need it, I got to have it. It's my lucky hat. I never fly without it.
露易絲  你知道我們所做的事有多嚴重嗎
Lois, do you understand what we are involved in here?
我管不了那麼多  沒有帽子  我就不上飛機
I don't care. I need my hat. I won't fly without it.
我能怎麼辦  她堅持要她的帽子
What could I do if she insisted I drive her home for her goddamn hat?
我把包裹藏在廚房  我只好帶她回去
I hid the package in the kitchen and went to take her home.
帽子
A hat?
這是什麼情況
What the fuck is this?
警察  別動  不許動  你這人渣
Police! Freeze! Don't you move, you motherfucker...
否則我會把你腦漿打出來  慢慢熄火
or I'll blow your brains out. Shut the car off slowly.
剎那之間  我以為我已經死了
For a second, I thought I was dead.
但當我聽到吵雜聲  我知道那些是警察
But when I heard all the noise, I knew they were cops.
只有條子  才用那種口氣說話
Only cops talk that way.
你他媽老實點
Don't fucking move.
如果是幫派兄弟  我會連一點聲音都聽不見
If they had been wiseguys, I wouldn't have heard a thing.
就被打死了
I would have been dead.
麥可  把門鎖上
Michael, lock the door!
餘波
你最後一次被捕是什麼時候
Talk to me. When was the last time you took a collar?
說呀
Fuckhead, I'm talking to you.
你一個字也不肯說  你什麼也不用說  我不在乎
You don't want to say a fucking word, don't. I don't really give a fuck.
等你要被關25年的時候  看你還能對你朋友多忠心
You'll do 25 years. See how much of a good guy you'll be then.
我一直以為直升機上的人
All day I thought the guys in the helicopter...
是為了德航劫案在跟蹤我  原來他們是緝毒組的
were local cops busting my balls over Lufthansa. They turned out to be narcs.
把律師叫來就好了
Just get the lawyer.
他們盯了我一個月了  竊聽電話  跟蹤行程  全套都來
They'd been on me a month. Phone taps, surveillance, everything.
你認識這些夥計  你的搭檔都被抓了
You know the boys. All the pals are here.
你要是不說  我會整晚像蒼蠅一樣叮咬你
You don't want to talk to me, you'll have a problem all night.
在紐約  這任何一項罪名都可以判你25年監禁
Each one of these counts holds 25-to-life in New York State.
25年呀  老兄  你身心都會受不了那種壓力的
Twenty-five fucking years, pal. I'll slap your fucking head inside out.
你們去哪兒  買雜貨呀
What, were you guys grocery shopping?
要做蛋糕呀  你也要做蛋糕呀
Are we going to make a cake? You going to make a fucking cake?
有沒有找到什麼好東西呀
You got anything good in there?
是不是白粉呀
Is it good?
再見啦  鳥蛋
Bye-bye, dickhead.
阿迪卡監獄見啦
See you in Attica, dick.
我跟吉米談過了  他願意給我一點錢
I spoke to Jimmy. He offered to give me some money.
他想知道發生什麼事了  他要跟你談談
He just wants to know what's happening. He just wants to talk to you.
去他的吉米  去他的錢
Fuck Jimmy and his money.
我一定得想辦法出去  把事情向保利擺平  否則我死定了
I got to straighten out everything with Paulie or I'm dead.
那也許你在裏面還安全點
Then you're better off staying in here.
他們在裏面一樣可以幹掉我  也許還更容易
They could whack me in here as easy as outside, maybe even easier.
他們都擔心我會把事情抖出來
They're afraid I'll rat them out.
他們已經在避我了  我在裏面遲早是死路一條
People are already walking away from me. I'm dead in here.
你一定要把我弄出去
You got to get me out.
凱倫終於讓她媽媽拿房子抵押  保我出來
Karen finally got her mother to put her house up for my bail and I was out.
我有種感覺  我一出監牢就會被殺
I remember I had this feeling I would be killed right outside the jail.
我知道保利還在生我的氣  他那種死脾氣的人
I knew Paulie was still pissed at me, and he's such a hothead.
我也替吉米擔心
And I was worried about Jimmy.
吉米自己也很清楚狀況  如果保利知道他跟我在搞販毒
See, Jimmy knew if Paulie found out he was into drug deals with me...
他會比我還先死
Paulie would have Jimmy whacked even before me.
情勢對我很不利
This is the bad time.
到家之後我才有點安全感
I didn't feel safe until I got home.
現在我要好好計劃保住性命  盡快把貨脫手
Now my plan was to stay alive long enough to sell off the dope...
躲起來一陣子  讓我慢慢把所有事情擺平
the cops never found, then disappear until I can get things straightened out.
操
Fuck!
- 凱倫  我藏起來的那批貨呢  - 我衝下馬桶了
- Where's the stuff I left, Karen? - I flushed it down the toilet.
你幹了什麼
You what?
我該怎麼辦  到處都是條子
What was I supposed to do? They were all over the house.
那是我們的全部財產  價值6萬塊  我需要那些錢
That was worth $60,000! I need that money! That's all we got!
我能怎麼辦  他們有搜查令
What was I supposed to do? They had a search warrant!
你為什麼要這麼做  我們只有那些錢
That's all the money we had! I was depending on that! Why did you do that?
我沒辦法  他們一定會找到的
I had to. They were going to find it!
- 他們絕不會找到的  - 我敢發誓
- They would have never found it! - They would have, I swear to you!
他們一定會找到的
They would've found it!
你為什麼要這樣做
Why did you do that?
- 他們一定會找到的  - 你為什麼要這樣做
- They would have found it. - Why did you do that, Karen?
我的天呀
Oh, my God!
- 我是迫不得已  - 我的天呀
- I had to do it. - Oh, my God.
保利  我真的很抱歉
Paulie, I'm really sorry.
我不知道該說什麼才好  我知道我犯了嚴重的錯誤
I don't know what else to say. I know I fucked up.
你搞砸了
Yeah, you fucked up.
但我現在沒事了
But I'm all right now.
你可以相信我  我拿我孩子做保證
I can be trusted now. I'm clean. On my kids, I'm clean.
你睜著眼對我說謊
You looked in my eyes and lied to me.
把我當冤大頭
You treated me like a fucking jerk.
毫無份量
Like I was never nothing to you.
你警告過我們  所以我更不敢向你說實話了
After what you said, I couldn't come to you.
我從那時起到現在
You know, I was ashamed.
都很慚愧
I'm ashamed now.
但是我已經走投無路了  保利
But I got nowhere else to go, Paulie.
我現在只有求你了  我真的需要你的幫助
You're all I've got. And I really need your help. I really do.
拿著
Take this.
從現在起我不認識你了
And now I've got to turn my back on you.
三千兩百塊
$3,200.
一生替他做事  他就給了我三千兩百塊
That's what he gave me. $3,200 for a lifetime.
連買棺材都不夠
It wasn't even enough to pay for the coffin.
- 我們得跑路了  - 我不想跑
- We got to get out. - I don't want to run.
難道你要我放棄一切  找地方躲起來嗎
I don't want to. Am I supposed to pick up and leave everything? Go hiding?
我不要  那就是你所要的生活嗎
I don't want to do that. Is that what you want?
我們留在這裏  我們就死定了
If we stay around here, we're dead.
死定了  懂不懂
You got it? We're dead.
他們說得沒錯
They're right.
你藥嗑太多了  你已經完全神經過敏了
You took too much of that stuff. You're totally paranoid.
他還好吧  有沒有找他麻煩
How's he doing? Busting his balls or what?
他還好
He's okay.
他把嗑藥的毛病改掉了
They sobered him up.
那就好
Good. Very good. Glad to hear it.
他有沒有告訴你  條子問了他一些什麼樣的問題
You know what kind of questions they're asking him?
吉米  我不知道
Jimmy, I don't know.
我心情太亂了  我又沒有錢
I got my mind on so many other things. I got no money...
孩子們都已經會看報紙了
The girls are old enough to read the newspapers.
你回去叫他馬上給我打電話
Tell him he's got to call me. Okay?
我們要好好處理這件事  這是非常重要的
As soon as you talk to him, he's got to call me. It's important.
他不知道我來找你  他現在不是很正常
He doesn't know I came here to see you. It's like he's crazy.
- 先拿去救急  有幾千塊錢  - 謝了  吉米
- Take this. It's a couple of thousands. - Thanks, Jimmy.
不要太擔心好嗎  一切都會過去的
Don't worry, everything will be all right.
我有一批很漂亮的迪奧女裙
I got some beautiful Dior dresses. You want to have them?
去挑幾件喜歡的吧
Pick out a few for yourself.
- 挑給我媽媽  - 可以  沒問題  隨便挑
- For my mom. - Yeah, whatever.
不  不  是在轉角倉庫
No. It's over here. In the store on the corner.
因為是贓物  我放在角落
It's swag, so I got it down on the corner.
去吧  甜心  再見
Go ahead, sweetheart, I'll see you.
- 謝謝  吉米  - 不用擔心
- Thanks, Jimmy. - Don't worry.
- 我知道  - 不要忘了  打電話給我
- I'll try. - Don't forget, he's got to call me.
- 這邊嗎  - 一直走
- Over here? - Right down there.
一直走  在轉角
It's over there, on the corner.
就在那裏
Right there.
不是  去呀  就在裏面
No, go ahead. It's right in there.
不用了  吉米  我在趕時間
No, Jimmy. I'm in a hurry!
我媽在看孩子  我得回去
My mom's watching the kids! I got to get home!
以後再來拿
I'll come back later!
凱倫
Karen!
發生什麼事了
What happened?
沒事
Nothing.
- 到底什麼事  - 我只是突然怕起來了
- What happened? - I just got scared.
車鑰匙拿了沒有
Got the keys?
- 到底什麼事  - 我只是害怕起來了
- What happened, Karen? - I just got scared. It's okay.
- 沒事吧  - 現在沒事了
- Are you all right? - Yeah.
如果你是黑手黨員  你永遠不會知道幾時會被殺
If you're part of a crew, nobody ever tells you they're going to kill you.
沒人會事先通知你的
It doesn't happen that way.
也不像電影裏先大吵大罵
There aren't any arguments or curses like in the movies.
來殺你的人面帶笑容  像是你很親近的朋友
Your murderers come with smiles. They come as your friends.
他們一直很關心你
People who cared for you all your life.
在你有困難時  他們總會來幫助你
They always seem to come when you're weakest and most in need of their help.
所以我跟吉米約好在人多的地方見面
So I met Jimmy in a crowded place we both knew.
我早到了15分鐘  可吉米已經比我先到了
I got there 15 minutes early, and Jimmy was already there.
他佔了靠窗的雅座  凡是來餐廳的人  他都看得見
He took the booth near the window so he could see everyone who drove up.
他要確認我沒有被跟蹤
He wanted to make sure I wasn't tailed.
他很緊張  什麼也沒吃
He was jumpy. He hadn't touched a thing.
表面看來一點也沒事
On the surface, everything was supposed to be fine.
我們應該是要商量我的案子
We were supposed to be discussing my case.
但我可以感覺到吉米在試探我是否會為了救自己而出賣他
But I had a feeling Jimmy was trying to sense if I'd rat on him to save my neck.
我一直提醒你  不要在電話上談事情
I been telling you your whole life, don't talk on the phone.
現在你明白了
Now you understand?
我想你勝訴的機會很大  一切會沒問題的
It's going to be okay. You got a good chance to beat the case.
那個小子  你知道我是在說誰吧
You know that kid from the city we were talking about? You know?
那是個告密者  他一被捕就把所有的人都招供出來了
The kid turned out to be a rat. As soon as he got pinched, he ratted on everybody.
我知道他現在躲在哪裏
I know where he is. He's hiding now.
懂不懂我說的
Know what I'm saying?
你想你能和安東尼一方面度假  一方面把他解決掉嗎
Would you have a problem going with Anthony to take care of that?
沒問題
No, not at all.
這樣他們就沒證人了
That way they got nothing.
吉米從來沒有叫我替他除掉任何人
Jimmy had never asked me to whack somebody before.
現在他叫我和安東尼一起到佛羅里達去為他殺人
But now he's asking me to go to Florida and do a hit with Anthony.
那時候我就知道  如果我去了佛州  我不會活著回來
That's when I knew I would never have come back from Florida alive.
不論你要把我們搬去哪裏  我說過
Whenever you move me, I asked once and I'll tell you again...
我不去寒冷的地方
I don't want to go any place cold.
你並沒有選擇餘地
You don't have a choice in that matter.
到底是誰管這個
Come on. Whoever fucking controls it...
幫個忙  只要不是寒冷地方就行
just no place cold. Do that for me. I'm trying to...
他有氣管炎
He's bronchial, that's why.
如果檢查後他真有氣管炎  我們會列入考慮因素
If he's legitimately bronchial, we'll consider that.
我希望去不冷的地方
I'd like to go someplace not cold.
我能問一些問題嗎  我父母會怎麼樣
Can I ask you some questions? What about my parents?
他們怎麼啦
What about them?
我能不能見他們  跟他們通消息
Am I going to see them? Am I going to talk to them?
怎麼跟他們聯絡
Don't I have some kind of contact with them?
不能
No.
等一等  你是說
Wait a minute. Wait a minute. You mean to tell me that...
就算我父母生病了  我也不能去看他們嗎
God forbid something happens to my parents, they get sick, I can't see them?
也許可以特別安排  如果他們病了
Maybe something can be worked out if they're sick...
情形特殊的話
if there's extraordinary circumstances...
我不能這樣做  亨利
I can't do this. I can't do this, Henry.
我不能留下我父母不管
I can't leave my parents.
抱歉  凱倫  我跟你說了
Excuse me, Karen, I told you before.
除非你跟孩子們和我在一起  我不會同意這個證人保護行動
I'm not going to do this unless you and the kids come with me.
我沒有辦法一個人捱過這些
I can't do it without you.
你要怎麼做就怎麼做  可是  就這樣
So, you do whatever, but... that's it.
- 你們需要亨利  並不需要我  對不對  - 沒錯
- You need Henry, not me, right? - That's right.
老實說  我並不在乎你去不去
Frankly, I don't care whether you go or not.
如果能使他成為一個快樂而有用的證人  我希望你去
If it'll make him a better witness, I'd like you to be with him.
他們要的是亨利  不是我
They want Henry, not me.
亨利會受到保護  他們動不了他
Henry'll be in the protection program. They can't get to him.
他們只能從你跟孩子身上動手來傷害亨利
They can only get to him by getting to you or your kids.
假如他參與這次行動  你的處境就很危險
If he goes into the program, you're in danger...
- 我什麼也不知道呀  - 不要給我
- I don't know anything. - Don't give me...
天真無邪那一套
the babe-in-the-woods routine.
我聽過那些電話錄音  你在電話中大談白粉
I've listened to those wiretaps, and I've heard you talk about cocaine.
你跟亨利一通電話接著一通
Conversation after conversation you talked to Henry on the phone.
不管他是進監牢
It doesn't matter. Whether he goes to jail...
還是勝訴了  他都一樣是沒命
or stays on the streets and beats the case, he's a dead man.
你們心裏都很清楚
He knows it and you know it.
我們的孩子怎麼辦  他們要上學呀
What about the kids and school?
總不能把他們留下
Will they get left back? I mean, what goes on?
你們為什麼不到華爾街去抓那些真正的壞人
Go to Wall Street and get real crooks.
賣西裝給你們的人  真有幽默感
Whoever sold you those suits had a sense of humor.
歸根結底  和我們配合才是唯一救你們的方法
What it comes down to is we're your only salvation.
我們會保障你們的生命  也會不讓他去坐牢
We'll save your life and his life, and we'll keep you out of jail.
今天早上你曾把你的背景向陪審團說明
This morning you told the jury about your background.
要從人群中消失並不是一件困難的事
It was easy for us to disappear.
房子是岳母的名字
My house was in my mother-in-law's name.
車是我老婆的名字
My cars were registered to my wife.
社會福利卡以及駕照都是假的
My Social Security cards and driver's licenses were phonies.
沒投過票  沒繳過稅
I never voted or paid taxes.
唯一能表示有我這個人存在的是出生證明和犯罪記錄
My birth certificate and arrest sheet was all you'd ever have to know I was alive.
- 那個人在法庭內嗎  - 是的
- Do you see him here in this courtroom? - Yes.
你能為陪審團將他指證出來嗎
Will you please point him out for the jury?
法官大人  請記錄下來  希爾先生已正式指證了詹姆斯·康威
Let the record reflect that Mr. Hill identified the defendant, James Conway.
你也認識一位叫保羅·西席羅的人
Do you also know a man named Paul Cicero?
- 那個人在這個法庭內嗎  - 是的
- Do you see him in the courtroom? - Yes.
你能為陪審團將他指證出來嗎
Can you point him out for the jury?
法官大人  請記錄下希爾先生已指證了保羅·西席羅
Let the record reflect that Mr. Hill identified the defendant, Paul Cicero.
法官大人  我這裏有一份文件
Your Honor, I have a document...
對我來說  最困難的就是從那種生活方式中走出來
The hardest thing was leaving the life.
我還是喜愛那種生活
I still love the life.
我們像電影明星一樣被禮遇
We were treated like movie stars with muscle.
只要開口  要什麼有什麼
We had it all, just for the asking.
老婆  母親  孩子  人人都能享受
Our wives, mothers, kids, everybody rode along.
一包紙袋的珠寶藏在廚房
I had paper bags filled with jewelry stashed in the kitchen.
一缸白粉就放在床邊
I had a sugar bowl full of coke next to the bed.
稱為鼠輩  是因為老鼠為了求生存  什麼事都會做
People call them rats because rats do anything to survive. Isn't that right?
- 抗議  - 抗議成立
- Objection! - Objection sustained.
- 至於老鼠我就不知道了  - 你太瞭解了
- I know nothing about being a rat. - You know everything about it.
只要一通電話  什麼都有
Anything I wanted was a phone call away.
免費的汽車  城裏所有的黑幫分子玩樂的地方都能自由進出
Free cars. Keys to a dozen hideout flats all over the city.
一個週末可以下注兩三萬
I'd bet $20,000, $30,000 over a weekend...
也可以一周內把贏的錢全花光  有時候也借高利貸來還賭債
then blow the winnings in a week or go to the sharks to pay the bookies.
不過一點關係都沒有
It didn't matter.
錢花光了  我只要出去多搶一點就行了
It didn't mean anything. When I was broke I would go out and rob some more.
我們控制一切
We ran everything.
收買條子  收買律師  甚至收買法官
We paid off cops. We paid off lawyers. We paid off judges.
每個人都受賄  只要我們肯出錢
Everybody had their hands out. Everything was for the taking.
現在都結束了
And now it's all over.
難就難在這裏
That's the hardest part.
如今一切都不同了
Today everything is different.
我得像其他人一樣等排班
There's no action. I have to wait around like everyone else.
連像樣的菜都吃不到
Can't even get decent food.
我搬來以後曾點過意大利面  加意大利蕃茄配料
After I got here I ordered spaghetti with marinara sauce...
結果上的是雞蛋面加蕃茄醬
and I got egg noodles and ketchup.
我成為了無名小卒淡泊一生
I'm an average nobody.
下半輩子得過得像個可憐蟲
I get to live the rest of my life like a schnook.
亨利·希爾目前仍在接受證人保護行動
他於1987年在西雅圖以販毒罪名被捕
但得到緩刑五年  此後不曾再犯罪
1989年  亨利與凱倫在婚後25年正式離婚
保羅·西席羅因呼吸道問題1988年死於監獄  享年73歲
吉米·康威目前仍在紐約州監獄以謀殺的罪名服刑
他必須等到2004年  他78歲時才能獲得假釋